<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Root>
	<p>Basics</p>
	<p>Read me first</p>
	<p>Please read this manual before using the device to ensure safe and proper use.</p>
	<p>Descriptions are based on the device’s default settings.</p>
	<p>Some content may differ from your device depending on the region, service provider, model specifications, or device’s software.</p>
	<p>Content (high quality content) that requires high CPU and RAM usage will affect the overall performance of the device. Apps related to the content may not work properly depending on the device’s specifications and the environment that it is used in.</p>
	<p>Samsung is not liable for performance issues caused by apps supplied by providers other than Samsung.</p>
	<p>Samsung is not liable for performance issues or incompatibilities caused by edited registry settings or modified operating system software. Attempting to customise the operating system may cause the device or apps to work improperly.</p>
	<p>Software, sound sources, wallpapers, images, and other media provided with this device are licensed for limited use. Extracting and using these materials for commercial or other purposes is an infringement of copyright laws. Users are entirely responsible for illegal use of media.</p>
	<p>You may incur additional charges for data services, such as messaging, uploading and downloading, auto-syncing, or using location services depending on your data plan. For large data transfers, it is recommended to use the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature.</p>
	<p>Default apps that come with the device are subject to updates and may no longer be supported without prior notice. If you have questions about an app provided with the device, contact a Samsung Service Centre. For user-installed apps, contact service providers.</p>
	<p>Modifying the device’s operating system or installing softwares from unofficial sources may result in device malfunctions and data corruption or loss. These actions are violations of your Samsung licence agreement and will void your warranty.</p>
	<p>Depending on the region or service provider, a screen protector is attached for protection during production and distribution. Damage to the attached screen protector is not covered by the warranty.</p>
	<p>You can see the touchscreen clearly even in strong outdoor sunlight by automatically adjusting the contrast range based on the surrounding environment. Due to the nature of the product, displaying fixed graphics for extended periods may result in afterimages (screen burn-in) or ghosting.</p>
	<p>It is recommended not to use fixed graphics on part or all of the touchscreen for extended periods and turn off the touchscreen when not using the device.</p>
	<p>You can set the touchscreen to turn off automatically when you are not using it. Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Display</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Screen timeout</MMI>, and then select the length of time you want the device to wait before turning off the touchscreen.</p>
	<p>To set the touchscreen to automatically adjust its brightness based on the surrounding environment, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Display</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Adaptive brightness</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Depending on the region, you can view the regulatory information on the device. To view the information, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>About phone</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Regulatory information</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Maintaining water and dust resistance</p>
	<p>Your device supports water- and dust-resistance. Follow these tips carefully to maintain the water- and dust-resistance of your device. Failure to do so may result in damage to your device.</p>
	<p>Do not immerse the device in fresh water deeper than <C_NoBreak>1.5 m</C_NoBreak> or keep it submerged for more than <C_NoBreak>30 minutes</C_NoBreak>. If you immerse the device in any liquid other than fresh water, such as salt water, ionised water, or alcoholic beverage, liquid will enter the device faster.</p>
	<p>Do not expose the device to <C_Important-Semi>water moving with force</C_Important-Semi>.</p>
	<p>Do not open the device’s covers when the device is in water or in very humid places, such as swimming pools or bathrooms.</p>
	<p>Do not open the back cover using wet hands or when the device is wet.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>The rubber seal fitted to the back cover</C_Important-Semi> is an important component of the device. Take care when opening and closing the back cover to avoid damaging the rubber seal. Also, ensure that the rubber seal is free from debris, such as sand or dust to prevent damage to the device.</p>
	<p>The back cover may be loosened <C_Important-Semi>if the device is dropped or receives an impact</C_Important-Semi>. Ensure that all the covers are properly aligned and tightly closed.</p>
	<p>If the device is exposed to fresh water, dry it thoroughly with a clean, soft cloth. If the device is exposed to other liquids, such as salt water, swimming pool water, soapy water, oil, perfume, sunscreen, hand cleaner, or chemical products such as cosmetics, rinse it with fresh water and dry it thoroughly with a clean, soft cloth. If you do not follow these instructions, the device’s performance and appearance may be affected.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>If the device has been immersed in water or the microphone or speaker is wet</C_Important-Semi>, sound may not be heard clearly during a call. After wiping the device with a dry cloth, dry it thoroughly before using it.</p>
	<p>The touchscreen and other features may not work properly <C_Important-Semi>if the device is used in water</C_Important-Semi>.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>Your device has been tested in a controlled environment and certified to be waterand dust-resistant in specific situations (meets requirements of classification IP68 as described by the international standard IEC 60529-Degrees of Protection provided by Enclosures [IP Code]; test conditions: 15-35 °C, 86-106 kPa, fresh water, 1.5 metre, 30 minutes). Despite this classification, it is still possible for your device to be damaged in certain situations.</C_Important-Semi></p>
	<p>Instructional icons</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Warning</C_Important-Semi>: situations that could cause injury to yourself or others</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Caution</C_Important-Semi>: situations that could cause damage to your device or other equipment</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Notice</C_Important-Semi>: notes, usage tips, or additional information</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Device overheating situations and solutions</p>
	<p>When the device heats up while charging the battery</p>
	<p>While charging, the device and the charger may become hot. During wireless charging or fast charging, the device may feel hotter to the touch. This does not affect the device’s lifespan or performance and is in the device’s normal range of operation. If the battery becomes too hot, the charger may stop charging.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Heading3>Do the following when the device heats up:</Heading3><UnorderList_1-Cell>Disconnect the charger from the device and close any running apps. Wait for the device to cool down and then begin charging the device again.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If the lower part of the device overheats, it could be because the connected USB cable is damaged. Replace the damaged USB cable with a new Samsung-approved one.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>When using a wireless charger, do not place foreign materials, such as metal objects, magnets, and magnetic stripe cards, between the device and the wireless charger.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The wireless charging or fast charging feature is only available on supported models.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>When the device heats up during use</p>
	<p>When you use features or apps that require more power or use them for extended periods, your device may temporarily heat up due to increased battery consumption. Close any running apps and do not use the device for a while.</p>
	<p>The following are examples of situations in which the device may overheat. Depending on the functions and apps you use, these examples may not apply to your model.</p>
	<p>During the initial setup after purchase or when restoring data</p>
	<p>When downloading large files</p>
	<p>When using apps that require more power or using apps for extended periods</p>
	<p>When playing high-quality games for extended periods</p>
	<p>When recording videos for extended periods</p>
	<p>When streaming videos while using the maximum brightness setting</p>
	<p>When connecting to a TV</p>
	<p>While multitasking (or, when running many apps in the background)</p>
	<p>When using Multi window</p>
	<p>When updating or installing apps while recording videos</p>
	<p>When downloading large files during a video call</p>
	<p>When recording videos while using a navigation app</p>
	<p>When using large amount of data for syncing with the cloud, email, or other accounts</p>
	<p>When using a navigation app in a car while the device is placed in direct sunlight</p>
	<p>When using the mobile hotspot and tethering feature</p>
	<p>When using the device in areas with weak signals or no reception</p>
	<p>When charging the battery with a damaged USB cable</p>
	<p>When the device’s multipurpose jack is damaged or exposed to foreign materials, such as liquid, dust, metal powder, and pencil lead</p>
	<p>When you are roaming</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Heading3>Do the following when the device heats up:</Heading3><UnorderList_1-Cell>Keep the device updated with the latest software.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Conflicts between running apps may cause the device to heat up. Restart the device.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Deactivate the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak>, GPS, and Bluetooth features when not using them.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Close apps that increase battery consumption or that run in the background when not in use.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Delete unnecessary files or unused apps.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Decrease the screen brightness.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If the device overheats or feels hot for a prolonged period, do not use it for a while. If the device continues to overheat, contact a Samsung Service Centre.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Precautions for device overheating</p>
	<p>If you begin to feel uncomfortable due to the device overheating, stop using the device.</p>
	<p>When the device heats up, the features and performance may be limited or the device may turn off to cool down. The feature is only available on supported models.</p>
	<p>If the device overheats and reaches a certain temperature, a warning massage will appear to prevent device failure, skin irritations and damages, and battery leakage. To lower the device’s temperature, the screen brightness and the performance speed will be limited and battery charging will stop. Running apps will be closed and all calling and other features will be limited, except for emergency calls, until the device cools down.</p>
	<p>If the second message appears due to a further increase of the device’s temperature, the device will turn off. Do not use the device until the device’s temperature drops below the specified level. If the second warning message appears during an emergency call, the call will not be disconnected by a forced shut down.</p>
	<p>Precautions for operating environment</p>
	<p>Your device may heat up due to the environment in the following conditions. Use caution to avoid shortening the battery’s lifespan, damaging the device, or causing a fire.</p>
	<p>Do not store your device in very cold or very hot temperatures.</p>
	<p>Do not expose your device to direct sunlight for extended periods.</p>
	<p>Do not use or store your device for extended periods in very hot areas, such as inside a car in the summertime.</p>
	<p>Do not place the device in any areas that may overheat, such as on an electric heating mat.</p>
	<p>Do not store your device near or in heaters, microwaves, hot cooking equipment, or high pressure containers.</p>
	<p>Do not use a cable whose covering is peeled off or damaged, and do not use any charger or battery that is damaged or malfunctioning.</p>
	<p>Device layout and functions</p>
	<p>Package contents</p>
	<p>Refer to the quick start guide for package contents.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The items supplied with the device and any available accessories may vary depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The supplied items are designed only for this device and may not be compatible with other devices.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Appearances and specifications are subject to change without prior notice.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You can purchase additional accessories from your local Samsung retailer. Make sure they are compatible with the device before purchase.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use only Samsung-approved accessories. Using unapproved accessories may cause the performance problems and malfunctions that are not covered by the warranty.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Availability of all accessories is subject to change depending entirely on manufacturing companies. For more information about available accessories, refer to the Samsung website.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Device layout</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>When using the speakers, such as when playing media files or using speakerphone, do not place the device close to your ears.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Be careful not to expose the camera lens to a strong light source, such as direct sunlight. If the camera lens is exposed to a strong light source, such as direct sunlight, the camera image sensor may be damaged. A damaged image sensor is irreparable and will cause dots or spots in pictures.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you use the device with its glass or acrylic body broken, there may be a risk of injury. Use the device only after it has been repaired at a Samsung Service Centre.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Connectivity problems and battery drain may occur in the following situations:</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>If you attach metallic stickers on the antenna area of the device</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>If you attach a device cover made with metallic material to the device</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>If you cover the device’s antenna area with your hands or other objects while using certain features, such as calls or the mobile data connection</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Using a Samsung-approved screen protector is recommended. Unapproved screen protectors may cause the sensors to malfunction.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Do not cover the proximity sensor area with screen accessories, such as a screen protector, stickers, or a cover. Doing so may cause the sensor to malfunction.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Hard keys</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Function</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Volume key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press to adjust the device volume.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Side key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>When the device is off, press and hold to turn it on.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press to turn on or lock the screen.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press and hold to start a conversation with Bixby. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Using Bixby</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press twice or press and hold to launch the app or feature you set.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Place your finger on the Side key to register your fingerprints.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Side key</C_Important-Semi> + <C_Important-Semi>Volume Down key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press simultaneously to capture a screenshot.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press and hold simultaneously to turn off the device.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>XCover key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press or press and hold to launch preset apps.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Top key</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Press or press and hold to launch preset apps.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Setting the Side key</p>
	<p>Select an app or feature to launch by pressing the Side key twice or pressing and holding the Side key.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Side key</MMI>, and then select an option you want.</p>
	<p>Soft buttons</p>
	<p>When you turn on the screen, the soft buttons will appear at the bottom of the screen. The soft buttons are set to the Recents button, Home button, and Back button by default. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Navigation bar (soft buttons)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p>Installing the battery</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Be careful not to damage your fingernails when you remove the back cover.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Do not bend or twist the back cover excessively. Doing so may damage the cover.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Insert the battery with the battery’s gold-coloured contacts properly aligned with the device’s contacts.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Ensure that the back cover is closed tightly to prevent water and dust from entering the device. Open or loose back cover may allow water and dust to enter the device and cause damage.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Use only Samsung-approved back covers and accessories with the device.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Removing the battery</p>
	<p>Pull out the battery.</p>
	<p>Charging the battery</p>
	<p>Charge the battery before using it for the first time or when it has been unused for extended periods.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Use only Samsung-approved battery, charger, and cable specifically designed for your device. Incompatible battery, charger, and cable can cause serious injuries or damage to your device.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Connecting the charger improperly may cause serious damage to the device. Any damage caused by misuse is not covered by the warranty.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use only USB <C_NoBreak>Type-C</C_NoBreak> cable supplied with the device. The device may be damaged if you use Micro USB cable.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To save energy, unplug the charger when not in use. The charger does not have a power switch, so you must unplug the charger from the electric socket when not in use to avoid wasting power. The charger should remain close to the electric socket and easily accessible while charging.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Connect the USB cable to the USB power adaptor.</p>
	<p>Plug the USB cable into the device’s multipurpose jack.</p>
	<p>Plug the USB power adaptor into an electric socket.</p>
	<p>After fully charging, disconnect the charger from the device. Then, unplug the charger from the electric socket.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Do not remove the battery before removing the charger. This may damage the device.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Reducing the battery consumption</p>
	<p>Your device provides various options that help you conserve battery power.</p>
	<p>Optimise the device using the device care feature.</p>
	<p>When you are not using the device, turn off the screen by pressing the Side key.</p>
	<p>Activate power saving mode.</p>
	<p>Close unnecessary apps.</p>
	<p>Deactivate the Bluetooth feature when not in use.</p>
	<p>Deactivate auto-syncing of apps that need to be synced.</p>
	<p>Decrease the backlight time.</p>
	<p>Decrease the screen brightness.</p>
	<p>Battery charging tips and precautions</p>
	<p>When the battery power is low, the battery icon appears empty.</p>
	<p>If the battery is completely discharged, the device cannot be turned on immediately when the charger is connected. Allow a depleted battery to charge for a few minutes before turning on the device.</p>
	<p>If you use multiple apps at once, network apps, or apps that need a connection to another device, the battery will drain quickly. To avoid losing power during a data transfer, always use these apps after fully charging the battery.</p>
	<p>Using a power source other than the charger, such as a computer, may result in a slower charging speed due to a lower electric current.</p>
	<p>The device can be used while it is charging, but it may take longer to fully charge the battery.</p>
	<p>If the device receives an unstable power supply while charging, the touchscreen may not function. If this happens, unplug the charger from the device.</p>
	<p>While charging, the device and the charger may heat up. This is normal and should not affect the device’s lifespan or performance. If the battery gets hotter than usual, the charger may stop charging. If this occurs during wireless charging, disconnect the device from the charger to let it cool down, then charge the device again later.</p>
	<p>If you charge the device while the multipurpose jack is wet, the device may be damaged. Thoroughly dry the multipurpose jack before charging the device.</p>
	<p>If the device is not charging properly, take the device and the charger to a Samsung Service Centre.</p>
	<p>Fast charging</p>
	<p>The device has a built-in fast charging feature. You can charge the battery more quickly while the device or its screen is turned off.</p>
	<p>Increasing the charging speed</p>
	<p>To increase the charging speed, turn the device or its screen off when you charge the battery.</p>
	<p>If the fast charging feature is not activated, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Battery</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Fast cable charging</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>While charging, you cannot activate or deactivate this feature.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You cannot use the built-in fast charging feature when you charge the battery using a standard battery charger.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If the device heats up or the ambient air temperature rises, the charging speed may decrease automatically. This is a normal operating condition to prevent damage to the device.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>SIM or USIM card (nano-SIM card)</p>
	<p>Installing the SIM or USIM card</p>
	<p>Insert the SIM or USIM card provided by the mobile telephone service provider.</p>
	<p>For dual SIM models, you can insert two SIM or USIM cards so you can have two phone numbers or service providers for a single device. In some areas, data transfer speeds may be slower if two SIM cards are inserted in the device than when one SIM card is inserted.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use only a nano-SIM card.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use caution not to lose or let others use the SIM or USIM card. Samsung is not responsible for any damages or inconveniences caused by lost or stolen cards.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some services that require a network connection may not be available depending on the service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_SingleStep>►</C_SingleStep> <C_Important-Semi>Single SIM models</C_Important-Semi>:</p>
	<p><C_SingleStep>►</C_SingleStep> <C_Important-Semi>Dual SIM models</C_Important-Semi>:</p>
	<p>Remove the back cover and battery.</p>
	<p>Insert the SIM or USIM card with the gold-coloured contacts facing downwards.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Do not insert a memory card into the SIM card slot. If a memory card happens to be lodged in the SIM card slot, take the device to a Samsung Service Centre to remove the memory card.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Replace the battery and back cover.</p>
	<p><xref/>Using dual SIM or USIM cards (dual SIM models)</p>
	<p>If you insert two SIM or USIM cards, you can have two phone numbers or service providers for a single device.</p>
	<p>Activating SIM or USIM cards</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SIM card manager</MMI>. Select a SIM or USIM card and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Customising SIM or USIM cards</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SIM card manager</MMI>, and then select a SIM or USIM card to access the following options:</p>
	<p><MMI>Icon</MMI>: Change the icon of the SIM or USIM card.</p>
	<p><MMI>Name</MMI>: Change the display name of the SIM or USIM card.</p>
	<p><MMI>Network mode</MMI>: Select a network type to use with the SIM or USIM card.</p>
	<p>Setting preferred SIM or USIM cards</p>
	<p>When two cards are activated, you can assign voice calls, messaging, and data services to specific cards.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SIM card manager</MMI>, and then set the feature preferences for your cards in <MMI>Preferred SIM card</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Memory card (microSD card)</p>
	<p>Installing a memory card</p>
	<p>Your device’s memory card capacity may vary from other models and some memory cards may not be compatible with your device depending on the memory card manufacturer and type. To view your device’s maximum memory card capacity, refer to the Samsung website.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some memory cards may not be fully compatible with the device. Using an incompatible card may damage the device or the memory card, or corrupt the data stored in it.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use caution to insert the memory card right-side up.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The device supports the FAT and the exFAT file systems for memory cards. When inserting a card formatted in a different file system, the device will ask to reformat the card or will not recognise the card. To use the memory card, you must format it. If your device cannot format or recognise the memory card, contact the memory card manufacturer or a Samsung Service Centre.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Frequent writing and erasing of data shortens the lifespan of memory cards.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>When inserting a memory card into the device, the memory card’s file directory appears in the <MMI>My Files</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>SD card</MMI> folder.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Remove the back cover.</p>
	<p>Insert a memory card with the gold-coloured contacts facing downwards.</p>
	<p>Replace the back cover.</p>
	<p>Removing the memory card</p>
	<p>Before removing the memory card, first unmount it for safe removal.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Storage</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Advanced</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SD card</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Unmount</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Do not remove external storage, such as a memory card or USB storage, while the device is transferring or accessing information, or right after transferring data. Doing so can cause data to be corrupted or lost or cause damage to the external storage or device. Samsung is not responsible for losses, including loss of data, resulting from the misuse of external storage devices.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Formatting the memory card</p>
	<p>A memory card formatted on a computer may not be compatible with the device. Format the memory card on the device.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Storage</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Advanced</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SD card</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Format</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Before formatting the memory card, remember to make backup copies of all important data stored in the memory card. The manufacturer’s warranty does not cover loss of data resulting from user actions.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Turning the device on and off</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Follow all posted warnings and directions from authorised personnel in areas where the use of wireless devices is restricted, such as aeroplanes and hospitals.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Turning the device on</p>
	<p>Turning the device off</p>
	<p>To turn off the device, press and hold the Side key and the Volume Down key simultaneously. Alternatively, open the notification panel and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Power off</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To restart the device, tap <MMI>Restart</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can set the device to turn off when you press and hold the Side key. Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Side key</MMI>, and then tap <MMI>Power off menu</MMI> under <MMI>Press and hold</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Emergency mode</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can switch the device to emergency mode to reduce battery consumption. Some apps and functions will be restricted. In emergency mode, you can make an emergency call, send your current location information to others, sound an emergency alarm, and more.</p>
	<p>To activate emergency mode, press and hold the Side key and the Volume Down key simultaneously. Alternatively, open the notification panel and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Emergency mode</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To deactivate emergency mode, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Turn off Emergency mode</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The usage time left shows the time remaining before the battery power runs out. Usage time left may vary depending on your device settings and operating conditions.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Initial setup</p>
	<p>When you turn on your device for the first time or after performing a data reset, follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to set up your device.</p>
	<p>Press and hold the Side key for a few seconds to turn on the device.</p>
	<p>Select your preferred device language and select <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>The Home screen will appear.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If you do not connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network, you may not be able to set up some device features during the initial setup.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Samsung account</p>
	<p>Your Samsung account is an integrated account service that allows you to use a variety of Samsung services provided by mobile devices, TVs, and the Samsung website.</p>
	<p>To check the list of services that can be used with your Samsung account, visit <C_URL><xref>account.samsung.com</xref></C_URL>. For more information on Samsung accounts, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Samsung account</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Help</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Creating a Samsung account</p>
	<p>If you do not have a Samsung account, you should create one. You can create a Samsung account using your email address.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Create account</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete creating your account.</p>
	<p>Signing in to your Samsung account</p>
	<p>If you already have a Samsung account, sign in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add account</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Samsung account</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Alternatively, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Follow the on-screen instructions to complete signing in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p>Finding your ID and resetting your password</p>
	<p>If you forget your Samsung account ID or password, tap <MMI>Find ID</MMI> or <MMI>Reset password</MMI> on the Samsung account sign-in screen. You can find your ID or reset your password after you enter the required information.</p>
	<p>Removing your Samsung account</p>
	<p>When you remove your Samsung account from the device, your data, such as contacts or events, will also be removed.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Samsung account</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Personal info</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Remove account</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Remove</MMI>, enter your Samsung account password, and then tap <MMI>OK</MMI>.</p>
	<p><xref/>Transferring data from your previous device (Smart Switch)</p>
	<p>You can use Smart Switch to transfer data from your previous device to your new device.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Smart Switch</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>This feature may not be supported on some devices or computers.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Limitations apply. Visit <C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com/smartswitch</xref></C_URL> for details. Samsung takes copyright seriously. Only transfer content that you own or have the right to transfer.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Transferring data wirelessly</p>
	<p>Transfer data from your previous device to your device wirelessly via <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct.</p>
	<p>On the previous device, launch <MMI>Smart Switch</MMI>.</p>
	<p>If you do not have the app, download it from <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI> or <MMI>Play Store</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On your device, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Smart Switch</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Place the devices near each other.</p>
	<p>On the previous device, tap <MMI>Send data</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Wireless</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On your device, select an item to bring and tap <MMI>Transfer</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to transfer data from your previous device.</p>
	<p>Backing up and restoring data using external storage</p>
	<p>Transfer data using external storage, such as a microSD card.</p>
	<p>Back up data from your previous device to external storage.</p>
	<p>Insert or connect the external storage device to your device.</p>
	<p>On your device, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Smart Switch</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Restore</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to transfer data from external storage.</p>
	<p>Transferring backup data from a computer</p>
	<p>Transfer data between your device and a computer. You must download the Smart Switch computer version app from <C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com/smartswitch</xref></C_URL>. Back up data from your previous device to a computer and import the data to your device.</p>
	<p>On the computer, visit <C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com/smartswitch</xref></C_URL> to download Smart Switch.</p>
	<p>On the computer, launch Smart Switch.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If your previous device is not a Samsung device, back up data to a computer using a program provided by the device’s manufacturer. Then, skip to the fifth step.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Connect your previous device to the computer using the device’s USB cable.</p>
	<p>On the computer, follow the on-screen instructions to back up data from the device. Then, disconnect your previous device from the computer.</p>
	<p>Connect your device to the computer using the USB cable.</p>
	<p>On the computer, follow the on-screen instructions to transfer data to your device.</p>
	<p>Understanding the screen</p>
	<p>Controlling the touchscreen</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Do not allow the touchscreen to come into contact with other electrical devices. Electrostatic discharges can cause the touchscreen to malfunction.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To avoid damaging the touchscreen, do not tap it with anything sharp or apply excessive pressure to it with your fingertips.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>It is recommended not to use fixed graphics on part or all of the touchscreen for extended periods. Doing so may result in afterimages (screen burn-in) or ghosting.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The device may not recognise touch inputs close to the edges of the screen, which are outside of the touch input area.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>It is recommended to use fingers when you use the touchscreen.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Heading3>Tapping</Heading3><Description>Tap the screen.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Heading3>Tapping and holding</Heading3><Description>Tap and hold the screen for approximately <C_NoBreak>2 seconds</C_NoBreak>.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Heading3>Dragging</Heading3><Description>Tap and hold an item and drag it to the target position.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Heading3>Double-tapping</Heading3><Description>Double-tap the screen.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Heading3>Swiping</Heading3><Description>Swipe upwards, downwards, to the left, or to the right.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Heading3>Spreading and pinching</Heading3><Description>Spread two fingers apart or pinch on the screen.</Description></Cell><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Navigation bar (soft buttons)</p>
	<p>When you turn on the screen, the soft buttons will appear on the navigation bar at the bottom of the screen. The soft buttons are set to the Recents button, Home button, and Back button by default. The functions of the buttons can change according to the app currently being used or usage environment.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Button</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Function</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Recents</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Tap to open the list of recent apps.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Home</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Tap to return to the Home screen.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Tap and hold to launch the <MMI>Google Assistant</MMI> app.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Back</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Tap to return to the previous screen.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Hiding the navigation bar</p>
	<p>View files or use apps on a wider screen by hiding the navigation bar.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Display</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Navigation bar</MMI>, and then tap <MMI>Full screen gestures</MMI> under <MMI>Navigation type</MMI>. The navigation bar will be hidden and the gesture hints will appear. Tap <MMI>More options</MMI> and select an option you want.</p>
	<p><MMI>Swipe from bottom</MMI>: The gesture hints will appear where the soft buttons are located. To use the soft buttons, drag the gesture hint of the desired button upwards.</p>
	<p><MMI>Swipe from sides and bottom</MMI>:</p>
	<p>Swipe up from the bottom of the screen to move to the Home screen.</p>
	<p>Swipe up and hold to view the list of recent apps.</p>
	<p>Swipe inward from either side of the screen to return to the previous screen.</p>
	<p>Swipe inward from one of the bottom corners to launch the <MMI>Google Assistant</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>If you want to hide the gesture hints at the bottom of the screen, tap the <MMI>Gesture hints</MMI> switch to deactivate it.</p>
	<p>Home screen and Apps screen</p>
	<p>The Home screen is the starting point for accessing all of the device’s features. It displays widgets, shortcuts to apps, and more.</p>
	<p>The Apps screen displays icons for all apps, including newly installed apps.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The screen may appear differently depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Switching between Home and Apps screens</p>
	<p>On the Home screen, swipe upwards or downwards to open the Apps screen.</p>
	<p>To return to the Home screen, swipe upwards or downwards on the Apps screen. Alternatively, tap the Home button or the Back button.</p>
	<p>If you add the Apps button on the Home screen, you can open the Apps screen by tapping the button. On the Home screen, tap and hold an empty area, tap <MMI>Home screen settings</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Apps button</MMI> switch to activate it. The Apps button will be added at the bottom of the Home screen.</p>
	<p>Display the screen in landscape mode</p>
	<p>On the Home screen, tap and hold an empty area, tap <MMI>Home screen settings</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Rotate to landscape mode</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Rotate the device until it is horizontal to view the screen in landscape mode.</p>
	<p>Moving items</p>
	<p>Tap and hold an item, and then drag it to a new location. To move the item to another panel, drag it to the side of the screen.</p>
	<p>To add a shortcut to an app on the Home screen, tap and hold an item on the Apps screen, and then tap <MMI>Add to Home</MMI>. A shortcut to the app will be added on the Home screen.</p>
	<p>You can also move frequently used apps to the shortcuts area at the bottom of the Home screen.</p>
	<p>Creating folders</p>
	<p>Create folders and gather similar apps to quickly access and launch apps.</p>
	<p>On the Home screen or the Apps screen, tap and hold an app, and then drag it over another app.</p>
	<p>A new folder containing the selected apps will be created. Tap <MMI>Folder name</MMI> and enter a folder name.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>Adding more apps</C_Important-Semi></p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the folder. Tick the apps to add and tap <MMI>Done</MMI>. You can also add an app by dragging it to the folder.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>Moving apps from a folder</C_Important-Semi></p>
	<p>Tap and hold an app to drag it to a new location.</p>
	<p><C_Important-Semi>Deleting a folder</C_Important-Semi></p>
	<p>Tap and hold a folder, and then tap <MMI>Delete folder</MMI>. Only the folder will be deleted. The folder’s apps will be relocated to the Apps screen.</p>
	<p><xref/>Editing the Home screen</p>
	<p>On the Home screen, tap and hold an empty area, or pinch your fingers together to access the editing options. You can set the wallpaper, add widgets, and more. You can also add, delete, or rearrange Home screen panels.</p>
	<p>Adding panels: Swipe to the left, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Moving panels: Tap and hold a panel preview, and then drag it to a new location.</p>
	<p>Deleting panels: Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the panel.</p>
	<p><MMI>Themes</MMI>: Change the device’s theme. Visual elements of interface, such as colours, icons, and wallpapers, will change depending on the selected theme.</p>
	<p><MMI>Widgets</MMI>: Widgets are small apps that launch specific app functions to provide information and convenient access on your Home screen. Tap and hold a widget, and then drag it to the Home screen. The widget will be added on the Home screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Home screen settings</MMI>: Configure settings for the Home screen, such as the screen grid or layout.</p>
	<p>Displaying all apps on the Home screen</p>
	<p>Without using a separate Apps screen, you can set the device to display all apps on the Home screen. On the Home screen, tap and hold an empty area, and then tap <MMI>Home screen settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Home screen layout</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Home screen only</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Apply</MMI>.</p>
	<p>You can now access all your apps by swiping to the left on the Home screen.</p>
	<p>Indicator icons</p>
	<p>Indicator icons appear on the status bar at the top of the screen. The icons listed in the table below are most common.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The status bar may not appear at the top of the screen in some apps. To display the status bar, drag down from the top of the screen.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some indicator icons appear only when you open the notification panel.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The indicator icons may appear differently depending on the service provider or model.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Description-Center-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Icon</C_Important-Semi></Description-Center-Cell></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_Important-Semi>Meaning</C_Important-Semi></Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>No signal</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Signal strength</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Roaming (outside of normal service area)</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>GPRS network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>EDGE network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>UMTS network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>HSDPA network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>HSPA+ network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><C_Image/><C_NoBreak>/</C_NoBreak><C_Image/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>LTE network connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell><C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> connected</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Bluetooth feature activated</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Location services being used</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Call in progress</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Missed call</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>New text or multimedia message</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Alarm activated</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Mute mode activated</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Vibration mode activated</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Flight mode activated</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Error occurred or caution required</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Battery charging</Description-Cell></Cell><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Battery power level</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Lock screen</p>
	<p>Pressing the Side key turns off the screen and locks it. Also, the screen turns off and automatically locks if the device is not used for a specified period.</p>
	<p>To unlock the screen, swipe in any direction when the screen turns on.</p>
	<p>If the screen is off, press the Side key to turn on the screen.</p>
	<p>Changing the screen lock method</p>
	<p>To change the screen lock method, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Lock screen</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Screen lock type</MMI>, and then select a method.</p>
	<p>When you set a pattern, PIN, password, or your biometric data for the screen lock method, you can protect your personal information by preventing others from accessing your device. After setting the screen lock method, the device will require an unlock code whenever unlocking it.</p>
	<p><MMI>Swipe</MMI>: Swipe in any direction on the screen to unlock it.</p>
	<p><MMI>Pattern</MMI>: Draw a pattern with four or more dots to unlock the screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>PIN</MMI>: Enter a PIN with at least four numbers to unlock the screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Password</MMI>: Enter a password with at least four characters, numbers, or symbols to unlock the screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>None</MMI>: Do not set a screen lock method.</p>
	<p><MMI>Face</MMI>: Register your face to unlock the screen. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Face recognition</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can set your device to perform a factory data reset if you enter the unlock code incorrectly several times in a row and reach the attempt limit. Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Lock screen</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Secure lock settings</MMI>, unlock the screen using the preset screen lock method, and then tap the <MMI>Auto factory reset</MMI> switch to activate it.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Screen capture</p>
	<p>Capture a screenshot while using the device and write on, draw on, crop, or share the captured screen. You can capture the current screen and scrollable area.</p>
	<p>Use the following method to capture a screenshot. Captured screenshots will be saved in <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Key capture: Press the Side key and the Volume Down key simultaneously.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>It is not possible to capture a screenshot while using some apps and features.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>After capturing a screenshot, use the following options on the toolbar at the bottom of the screen:</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Capture the current content and the hidden content on an elongated page, such as a webpage. When you tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, the screen will automatically scroll down and more content will be captured.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Write or draw on the screenshot or crop a portion from the screenshot. The cropped area will be saved in <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Add tags to the screenshot. To search for screenshots by tag, tap <MMI>Search</MMI> at the top of the Apps screen. You can view the tags list and easily search for the screenshot you want.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Share the screenshot with others.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If the options are not visible on the captured screen, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Screenshots</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Screenshot toolbar</MMI> switch to activate it.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Notification panel</p>
	<p>When you receive new notifications, such as messages or missed calls, indicator icons appear on the status bar. To see more information about the icons, open the notification panel and view the details.</p>
	<p>To open the notification panel, drag the status bar downwards. To close the notification panel, swipe upwards on the screen.</p>
	<p>You can use the following functions on the notification panel.</p>
	<p>Using quick setting buttons</p>
	<p>Tap quick setting buttons to activate certain features. Swipe downwards on the notification panel to view more buttons.</p>
	<p>To change feature settings, tap the text under each button. To view more detailed settings, tap and hold a button.</p>
	<p>To rearrange buttons, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Button order</MMI>, tap and hold a button, and then drag it to another location.</p>
	<p>Controlling media playback</p>
	<p>Take control of music or video playback easily using the Media feature. You can also continue playback on another device.</p>
	<p>Open the notification panel and tap <MMI>Media</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the icons on the controller to control the playback.</p>
	<p>To continue playback on another device, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select the device you want.</p>
	<p>Entering text</p>
	<p>Keyboard layout</p>
	<p>A keyboard appears automatically when you enter text to send messages, create notes, and more.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Text entry is not supported in some languages. To enter text, you must change the input language to one of the supported languages.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Changing the input language</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Languages and types</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Manage input languages</MMI> and select the languages to use. When you select two or more languages, you can switch between the input languages by swiping to the left or right on the space key.</p>
	<p><xref/>Changing the keyboard</p>
	<p>To change the keyboard type, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Languages and types</MMI>, select a language, and then select the keyboard type you want.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>On a <MMI>3x4 keyboard</MMI>, a key has three or four characters. To enter a character, tap the corresponding key repeatedly until the desired character appears.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some features may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Predict words based on your input and show word suggestions. To return to the keyboard functions list, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Enter emoticons.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Enter stickers. You can also enter My Emoji stickers that look like you. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Using My Emoji stickers in chats</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Attach animated GIFs.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Enter text by voice.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Change the keyboard settings.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Add an item from the clipboard.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Change the keyboard mode or size.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Open the text editing panel.</p>
	<p>Copying and pasting</p>
	<p>Tap and hold over text.</p>
	<p>Drag <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> or <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to select the desired text, or tap <MMI>Select all</MMI> to select all text.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Copy</MMI> or <MMI>Cut</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The selected text is copied to the clipboard.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold where the text is to be inserted and tap <MMI>Paste</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To paste text that you have previously copied, tap <MMI>Clipboard</MMI> and select the text.</p>
	<p>Dictionary</p>
	<p>Look up definitions for words while using certain features, such as when browsing webpages.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold over a word that you want to look up.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Dictionary</MMI> on the options list.</p>
	<p>If a dictionary is not preinstalled on the device, tap <MMI>Move to Manage dictionaries</MMI>, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> next to a dictionary, and then tap <MMI>Install</MMI> to download it.</p>
	<p>View the definition in the dictionary pop-up window.</p>
	<p>To switch to the full screen view, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. Tap the definition on the screen to view more definitions. In the detailed view, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to add the word to your favourite words list or tap <MMI>Search Web</MMI> to use the word as a search term.</p>
	<p>Apps and features</p>
	<p>Installing or uninstalling apps</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Galaxy Store</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Purchase and download apps. You can download apps that are specialised for Samsung Galaxy devices.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI> app.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This app may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Browse apps by category or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to search for a keyword.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To change the auto update settings, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Settings</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Auto update apps</MMI>, and then select an option.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Play Store</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Purchase and download apps.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Play Store</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Installing apps</p>
	<p>Browse apps by category or search for apps by keyword.</p>
	<p>Select an app to view information about it. To download free apps, tap <MMI>Install</MMI>. To purchase and download apps where charges apply, tap the price and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To change the auto update settings, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Settings</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Auto-update apps</MMI>, and then select an option.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Managing apps</p>
	<p>Uninstalling or disabling apps</p>
	<p>Tap and hold an app and select an option.</p>
	<p><MMI>Disable</MMI>: Disable selected default apps that cannot be uninstalled from the device.</p>
	<p><MMI>Uninstall</MMI>: Uninstall downloaded apps.</p>
	<p>Enabling apps</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Apps</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Disabled</MMI>, select an app, and then tap <MMI>Enable</MMI>.</p>
	<p><xref/>Setting app permissions</p>
	<p>For some apps to operate properly, they may need permission to access or use information on your device.</p>
	<p>To view your app permission settings, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Apps</MMI>. Select an app and tap <MMI>Permissions</MMI>. You can view the app’s permissions list and change its permissions.</p>
	<p>To view or change app permission settings by permission category, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Apps</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Permission manager</MMI>. Select an item and select an app.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If you do not grant permissions to apps, the basic features of the apps may not function properly.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Finder</p>
	<p>Search for content on the device quickly.</p>
	<p>On the Apps screen, tap <MMI>Search</MMI>. Alternatively, open the notification panel, swipe downwards, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Enter a keyword.</p>
	<p>Apps and content on your device will be searched.</p>
	<p>If you tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the keyboard, you can search for more content.</p>
	<p><xref/>Bixby</p>
	<p>Bixby is a user interface that helps you use your device more conveniently.</p>
	<p>You can talk to Bixby or type text. Bixby will launch a function you request or show the information you want. It also learns your usage patterns and environments. The more it learns about you, the more precisely it will understand you.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use Bixby, your device must be connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use Bixby, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Bixby is only available in some languages, and certain features may not be available depending on your region.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Starting Bixby</p>
	<p>When you launch Bixby for the first time, the Bixby intro page will appear. You must select the language to use with Bixby, sign in to your Samsung account according to the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions, and then agree to the terms and conditions.</p>
	<p>Press and hold the Side key. Alternatively, launch the <MMI>Bixby</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Select the language to use with Bixby.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Sign in to Samsung account</MMI> and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to sign in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If you are already signed in, your account information will appear on the screen.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Follow the on-screen instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>The Bixby screen will appear.</p>
	<p><xref/>Using Bixby</p>
	<p>When you say what you want to Bixby, Bixby will launch corresponding functions or show the information you requested.</p>
	<p>While pressing and holding the Side key, say what you want to Bixby, and then release your finger from the key when you are finished speaking. Alternatively, say “Hi, Bixby”, and when the device emits a sound, say what you want.</p>
	<p>For example, while pressing and holding the Side key, say “How’s the weather today?” The weather information will appear on the screen.</p>
	<p>If you want to know the weather tomorrow, while pressing and holding the Side key, just say “Tomorrow?” Because Bixby understands the context of the conversation, it will show you tomorrow’s weather.</p>
	<p>If Bixby asks you a question during a conversation, while pressing and holding the Side key, answer Bixby. Or, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and answer Bixby.</p>
	<p>If you are using headphones or Bluetooth audio, or start a conversation by saying “Hi, Bixby”, you can continue the conversation without tapping the icon. Launch the <MMI>Bixby</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Automatic listening</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Hands-free only</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Waking up Bixby using your voice</p>
	<p>You can start a conversation with Bixby by saying “Hi, Bixby”. Register your voice so that Bixby will respond to your voice when you say “Hi, Bixby”.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Bixby</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Voice wake-up</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the <MMI>Wake with “Hi, Bixby”</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>Now you can say “Hi, Bixby”, and when the device emits a sound, start a conversation.</p>
	<p>Communicating by typing text</p>
	<p>If your voice is not recognised due to noisy environments or if you are in a situation where speaking is difficult, you can communicate with Bixby via text.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Bixby</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, and then type what you want.</p>
	<p>During the communication, Bixby also will answer you through text instead of voice feedback.</p>
	<p>Bixby Vision is a service that provides various features based on image recognition.</p>
	<p>You can use Bixby Vision to quickly search for information by recognising objects or your current location. You can also experience the AR feature, which makes virtual images appear on the preview screen.</p>
	<p>Use a variety of useful Bixby Vision features.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use this feature, the device must be connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use some Bixby Vision features, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The available features and search results may vary depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>This feature may not be available or you may not get correct search results depending on the image size, format, or resolution.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Samsung is not responsible for the product information provided by Bixby Vision.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launching Bixby Vision</p>
	<p>Launch Bixby Vision using one of these methods.</p>
	<p>In the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list and tap <MMI>BIXBY VISION</MMI>.</p>
	<p>In the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, select an image and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>In the <MMI>Internet</MMI> app, tap and hold an image and tap <MMI>Bixby Vision</MMI>.</p>
	<p>If you added the Bixby Vision app icon to the Apps screen, launch the <MMI>Bixby Vision</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Searching for similar images</p>
	<p>Search for images similar to the recognised object online. You can view various images with properties similar to the object, such as colour or shape.</p>
	<p>For example, if you want to know the title of a photo or image, use the Bixby Vision features. The device will search for and show you related information or images with similar characteristics.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Lens</MMI> and keep the object within the screen to recognise it.</p>
	<p>Select a search result with <MMI>Images</MMI> on it.</p>
	<p>The similar images will appear.</p>
	<p>Translating or extracting text</p>
	<p>Recognise and show the translated text on the screen. You can also extract text from a document or an image file.</p>
	<p>For example, if you want to know what a sign says while travelling abroad, use the Bixby Vision features. The device will translate the sign’s text into the language you select.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and keep the text within the screen to recognise it.</p>
	<p>The translated text will appear on the screen.</p>
	<p>To extract text, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. You can share or save the extracted text.</p>
	<p>To save the screen with the translated text as an image, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. The screen will be saved in <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To change the source or target language, tap the language settings panel at the top of the screen.</p>
	<p>Searching for places</p>
	<p>Search for information about nearby places by recognising your current location. You can also view deals available nearby.</p>
	<p>For example, if you want to search for nearby stores having sales, use the Bixby Vision features. The device will search for and show you the sales happening in the nearby stores.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Available features may vary depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and point the camera towards the direction you want to search for places.</p>
	<p>You can view basic information about nearby places.</p>
	<p>If you want to search for places in another direction, point the camera towards the direction.</p>
	<p>You can view your current location and weather information. To view your current location on the map, point the camera towards the ground. To view the current weather information, point the camera towards the sky.</p>
	<p>Select a search result on the screen.</p>
	<p>The device will show the information of nearby places and deals.</p>
	<p>Experiencing various AR features</p>
	<p>Various apps include the AR feature, which makes virtual images appear on the background or person on the preview screen. You can conveniently experience products and view information without visiting stores or trying them in person. Experience Bixby Vision’s fun and useful AR feature.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Available apps may vary depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list, and then tap <MMI>BIXBY VISION</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Apps</MMI> and select the feature you want.</p>
	<p>Bixby Home</p>
	<p>On the Bixby Home screen, you can view recommended services and information that Bixby provides by analysing your usage patterns and your routine.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To view more content, connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To fully use this feature, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Opening Bixby Home</p>
	<p>When launching this feature for the first time or after performing a data reset, follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>Swipe upwards or downwards to view recommended content.</p>
	<p>To close Bixby Home, swipe to the left on the screen or tap the Back button.</p>
	<p>Using recommended content on Bixby Home</p>
	<p>When you open Bixby Home, you can view the content that is frequently updated as cards. Swipe upwards or downwards to view the cards.</p>
	<p>For example, on the way to the office in the morning, you can view your day’s schedule and play your favourite music on the Bixby Home screen.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The content and order of the cards update automatically at a specified interval. You can update cards whenever you want by swiping downwards on the screen.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Editing cards list</p>
	<p>To pin a card to the top of the Bixby Home screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Pin to top</MMI>. To unpin a card, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Unpin</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To stop displaying a card on the list, drag the card to the right and tap <MMI>Don’t show again</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To hide a card from the list, drag the card to the right and tap <MMI>Hide for now</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Selecting apps to show as cards</p>
	<p>Add or delete apps to show as cards on the Bixby Home screen.</p>
	<p>On the Bixby Home screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Cards</MMI>, select an app, and then tap the switches next to items to add or delete them.</p>
	<p>Customising the Bixby Home settings</p>
	<p>On the Bixby Home screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Customisation Service</MMI>: Set to use Bixby’s interactive and customised services to enhance your experience.</p>
	<p><MMI>Bixby Home content providers</MMI>: Read and agree to or withdraw your agreement from the terms and conditions and privacy policies of each content provider.</p>
	<p><MMI>Privacy Policy</MMI>: View the terms and conditions and privacy policies of each content provider.</p>
	<p><MMI>About Bixby Home</MMI>: View the Bixby Home version and legal information.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Bixby Routines</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Bixby Routines are a service that automates settings you use repeatedly and suggests useful features according to your frequent situations by learning your usage patterns.</p>
	<p>For example, a ‘before bed’ routine will perform actions, such as turning on silent mode and dark mode, to not be jarring on your eyes and ears when you use the device before going to bed.</p>
	<p>Adding routines</p>
	<p>Add routines to use your device more conveniently. When you add a routine, you can set its running condition to auto or manual.</p>
	<p>Adding recommended routines</p>
	<p>When your device learns your usage patterns, it will recommend adding useful or frequently used features as routines.</p>
	<p>When the recommendation notification appears, tap <MMI>View all</MMI> and add it as your own routine.</p>
	<p>Adding routines from the recommendation list</p>
	<p>View the list of useful features and add them as your own routines.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bixby Routines</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On the <MMI>Discover</MMI> list, select a routine you want and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To set the routine’s conditions and actions, tap <MMI>Edit</MMI>. Alternatively, tap the condition or action you want to edit.</p>
	<p>If you want to set the routine’s running condition to manual, tap <MMI>Start button tapped</MMI>. This option will appear only when there are no running conditions set.</p>
	<p>For manual routines, you can add them to the Home screen as widgets and access them quickly. When a pop-up window appears, tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Adding your own routines</p>
	<p>Add features you want to use as routines.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bixby Routines</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, set conditions, and then tap <MMI>Next</MMI>.</p>
	<p>If you want to set the routine’s running condition to manual, tap <MMI>Start button tapped</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, set actions, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter a routine name and tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>For manual routines, you can add them to the Home screen as widgets and access them quickly. When a pop-up windows appears, tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Using routines</p>
	<p>Running auto routines</p>
	<p>Auto routines will run automatically when their conditions are detected.</p>
	<p>Running manual routines</p>
	<p>For manual routines which you set the running condition as <MMI>Start button tapped</MMI>, you can run them manually by tapping the button whenever you want.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bixby Routines</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>My routines</MMI> and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> next to the routine you want to run. Alternatively, tap the routine’s widget on the Home screen.</p>
	<p>Viewing running routines</p>
	<p>Currently running routines will appear on the notification panel. To view a routine’s details, tap the notification.</p>
	<p>Stopping running routines</p>
	<p>You can quickly stop running routines. On the notification panel, select a routine and tap <MMI>Stop</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Managing routines</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bixby Routines</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>My routines</MMI>. Your routines will appear.</p>
	<p>To deactivate a routine, tap the routine’s switch or <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>To edit a routine, select a routine and tap <MMI>Edit</MMI>. Alternatively, tap the condition or action you want to edit.</p>
	<p>To delete routines, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Delete</MMI>, tick routines to delete, and then tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Reminder</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Create reminders to schedule to-do items or to view content later. You will receive notifications at the preset time or location for each reminder.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To receive more accurate notifications, connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To fully use this feature, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use location reminders, the GPS feature must be activated.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Starting Reminder</p>
	<p>Starting Reminder from Bixby Home</p>
	<p>On the Home screen, swipe to the right.</p>
	<p>The Bixby Home screen will appear.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Get started</MMI> on the <MMI>Reminder</MMI> card.</p>
	<p>The Reminder screen will appear and the <MMI>Reminder</MMI> app icon (<C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>) will be added to the Apps screen.</p>
	<p>Starting Reminder from Calendar</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reminder</MMI>. The Reminder screen will appear and the <MMI>Reminder</MMI> app icon (<C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>) will be added to the Apps screen.</p>
	<p>Create reminders with various methods. Reminder will alert you if you create a reminder with a specified time or location setting. You can also save various content, such as a single memo or webpage address, and view it later.</p>
	<p>For example, create a reminder to alert you to ‘Water the flowers when I get home’.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Reminder</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Write a reminder</MMI> or <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and enter ‘Water the flowers’.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Place</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Pick a place</MMI> and set the location to home.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>When I arrive at</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Save</MMI> to save the reminder.</p>
	<p>When you arrive at home, the ‘Water the flowers’ notification will appear.</p>
	<p>Checking reminder notifications</p>
	<p>At the preset time or location, a notification pop-up window will appear. Tap <MMI>Complete</MMI> or <MMI>Snooze</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Viewing the reminders list</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Reminder</MMI> app to view your reminders list. To view reminder details, select a reminder.</p>
	<p>Editing reminder details</p>
	<p>Add or edit reminder details, such as frequency, date and time, or location.</p>
	<p>On the reminders list, select a reminder to edit and tap <MMI>Edit</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Edit the conditions and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Completing reminders</p>
	<p>Mark reminders that you do not need to be reminded of as complete.</p>
	<p>On the reminders list, select a reminder and tap <MMI>Complete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Restoring reminders</p>
	<p>Restore reminders that have been completed.</p>
	<p>On the reminders list, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Completed</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Edit</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tick items to restore and tap <MMI>Restore</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Reminders will be added to the reminders list and you will be reminded at the preset times.</p>
	<p>Deleting reminders</p>
	<p>To delete a reminder, select a reminder and tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>. To delete multiple reminders, tap and hold a reminder, tick reminders to delete, and then tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Phone</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Make or answer voice and video calls.</p>
	<p>Making calls</p>
	<p>Enter a phone number.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to make a voice call, or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to make a video call.</p>
	<p>Making calls from call logs or contacts list</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Recents</MMI> or <MMI>Contacts</MMI>, and then swipe to the right on a contact or a phone number to make a call.</p>
	<p>If this feature is deactivated, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Motions and gestures</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Swipe to call or send messages</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Using speed dial</p>
	<p>Set speed dial numbers to quickly make calls.</p>
	<p>To set a number to speed dial, launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Keypad</MMI> or <MMI>Contacts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Speed dial numbers</MMI>, select a speed dial number, and then add a phone number.</p>
	<p>To make a call, tap and hold a speed dial number on the keypad. For speed dial numbers 10 and up, tap the first digit(s) of the number, and then tap and hold the last digit.</p>
	<p>For example, if you set the number <C_Important-Semi>123</C_Important-Semi> as a speed dial number, tap <C_Important-Semi>1</C_Important-Semi>, tap <C_Important-Semi>2</C_Important-Semi>, and then tap and hold <C_Important-Semi>3</C_Important-Semi>.</p>
	<p>Making calls from the locked screen</p>
	<p>Making calls by searching for nearby places</p>
	<p>You can easily make calls to places near your current location by searching for their information. You can search for nearby places by category, such as restaurants or stores, or by selecting recommended hot places.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Places</MMI>, and then select a category or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and enter a business name in the search field. Or, select one from the recommended hot places. The business’s information, such as its phone number or address, will appear.</p>
	<p>Making an international call</p>
	<p>Tap and hold <C_Important-Semi>0</C_Important-Semi> until the <C_Important-Semi>+</C_Important-Semi> sign appears.</p>
	<p>Enter the country code, area code, and phone number, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Receiving calls</p>
	<p>Answering a call</p>
	<p>Rejecting a call</p>
	<p>When a call comes in, drag <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> outside the large circle.</p>
	<p>To send a message when rejecting an incoming call, drag the <MMI>Send message</MMI> bar upwards and select a message to send. If the <MMI>Add reminder</MMI> switch is activated, a reminder will be saved to alert you of the rejected call one hour later.</p>
	<p>To create various rejection messages, launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Quick decline messages</MMI>, enter a message, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Missed calls</p>
	<p>If a call is missed, the <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> icon appears on the status bar. Open the notification panel to view the list of missed calls. Alternatively, launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Recents</MMI> to view missed calls.</p>
	<p>Blocking phone numbers</p>
	<p>Block calls from specific numbers added to your block list.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Block numbers</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Recents</MMI> or <MMI>Contacts</MMI>, select contacts or phone numbers, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To manually enter a number, tap <MMI>Add phone number</MMI>, enter a phone number, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>When blocked numbers try to contact you, you will not receive notifications. The calls will be logged in the call log.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can also block incoming calls from people that do not show their caller ID. Tap the <MMI>Block unknown callers</MMI> switch to activate the feature.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Options during calls</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If the area around the rear camera is covered, unwanted noises may incur during a call. Remove accessories, such as a screen protector or stickers, around the rear camera area.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>During a voice call</p>
	<p>The following actions are available:</p>
	<p><MMI>Add call</MMI>: Dial a second call. The first call will be put on hold. When you end the second call, the first call will be resumed.</p>
	<p><MMI>Hold call</MMI>: Hold a call. Tap <MMI>Resume call</MMI> to retrieve the held call.</p>
	<p><MMI>Bluetooth</MMI>: Switch to a Bluetooth headset if it is connected to the device.</p>
	<p><MMI>Keypad</MMI> / <MMI>Hide</MMI>: Open or close the keypad.</p>
	<p>During a video call</p>
	<p>Tap the screen to use the following options:</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Access additional options.</p>
	<p><MMI>Camera</MMI>: Turn off the camera so that the other party cannot see you.</p>
	<p><MMI>Switch</MMI>: Switch between the front and rear cameras.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : End the current call.</p>
	<p><MMI>Mute</MMI>: Turn off the microphone so that the other party cannot hear you.</p>
	<p><MMI>Speaker</MMI>: Activate or deactivate the speakerphone. When using the speakerphone, keep the device away from your ears.</p>
	<p>Adding a phone number to Contacts</p>
	<p>Adding a phone number to Contacts from the keypad</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Keypad</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter the number.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add to Contacts</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Adding a phone number to Contacts from the calls list</p>
	<p>Tap a caller’s image and tap <MMI>Add</MMI>, or tap a phone number and tap <MMI>Add to Contacts</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Create new contact</MMI> to create a new contact, or tap <MMI>Update existing contact</MMI> to add the number to an existing contact.</p>
	<p>Adding a tag to a phone number</p>
	<p>You can add tags to numbers without saving them to Contacts. This allows you to view the caller’s information when they call without having them listed in Contacts.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Phone</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Recents</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap a phone number <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add note</MMI>, enter a tag, and then tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>When a call comes from that number, the tag will show under the number.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Contacts</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Create new contacts or manage contacts on the device.</p>
	<p>Adding contacts</p>
	<p>Creating a new contact</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Depending on the selected storage location, the types of information you can save may vary.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Importing contacts</p>
	<p>Add contacts by importing them from other storages to your device.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Manage contacts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Import or export contacts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Import</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a storage location to import contacts from.</p>
	<p>Tick VCF files or contacts to import and tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a storage location to save contacts to and tap <MMI>Import</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Syncing contacts with your web accounts</p>
	<p>Sync your device contacts with online contacts saved in your web accounts, such as your Samsung account.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI> and select the account to sync with.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Sync account</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>For the Samsung account, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Sync settings</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Searching for contacts</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Use one of the following search methods:</p>
	<p>Scroll up or down the contacts list.</p>
	<p>Drag a finger along the index at the right side of the contacts list to scroll through it quickly.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> at the top of the contacts list and enter search criteria.</p>
	<p>Tap the contact. Then take one of the following actions:</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Add to favourite contacts.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> / <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Make a voice or video call.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Compose a message.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Compose an email.</p>
	<p>Sharing contacts</p>
	<p>You can share contacts with others by using various sharing options.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Share</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select contacts and tap <MMI>Share</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a sharing method.</p>
	<p>Saving and sharing profile</p>
	<p>Save and share your profile information, such as your photo and status message, with others using the profile sharing feature.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use this feature, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The profile sharing feature may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The profile sharing feature is only available for contacts who have activated the profile sharing feature on their device.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and select your profile.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Edit</MMI>, edit your profile, and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Tap here to share your profile</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>To use the profile sharing feature, your phone number must be verified. You can view your contacts’ updated profile information in <MMI>Contacts</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To change the scope of contacts to share your profile with, tap <MMI>Select what’s shared</MMI>, select an item to share, and then select an option.</p>
	<p>Creating groups</p>
	<p>You can add groups, such as family or friends, and manage contacts by group.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Groups</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Create group</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter a group name.</p>
	<p>To set a group ringtone, tap <MMI>Group ringtone</MMI> and select a ringtone.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add member</MMI>, select contacts to add to the group, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Sending a group message</p>
	<p>You can send a group message to a group’s members at the same time.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Groups</MMI>, select a group, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Send message</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Merging duplicate contacts</p>
	<p>When you import contacts from other storages, or sync contacts with other accounts, your contacts list may include duplicate contacts. Merge duplicate contacts into one to streamline your contacts list.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Manage contacts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Merge contacts</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tick contacts and tap <MMI>Merge</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Deleting contacts</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select contacts and tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To delete contacts one by one, open the contacts list and tap a contact. Then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Messages</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Send and view messages by conversation.</p>
	<p>Sending messages</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You may incur additional charges for sending messages when you are roaming.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Add recipients and enter a message.</p>
	<p>To record and send a voice message, tap and hold <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, say your message, and then release your finger. The recording icon appears only while the message input field is empty.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to send the message.</p>
	<p>Viewing messages</p>
	<p>Messages are grouped into message threads by contact.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You may incur additional charges for receiving messages when you are roaming.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>To reply to the message, tap the message input field, enter a message, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>To adjust the font size, spread two fingers apart or pinch on the screen.</p>
	<p>Blocking unwanted messages</p>
	<p>Block messages from specific numbers added to your block list.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Block numbers and messages</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Block numbers</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Conversations</MMI> and select a contact or a phone number. Or, tap <MMI>Contacts</MMI>, select contacts, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To manually enter a number, enter a phone number under <MMI>Enter phone number</MMI> and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Setting the message notification</p>
	<p>You can change notification sound, display options, and more.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Notifications</MMI>, and then tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Setting a message reminder</p>
	<p>You can set an alert at an interval to let you know that you have unchecked notifications. If this feature is not activated, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Accessibility</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Advanced settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Notification reminders</MMI>, and then tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Deleting messages</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Conversations</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On the messages list, select a contact or a phone number.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold a message, then tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To delete multiple messages, tick messages you want to delete.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Internet</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Browse the Internet to search for information and bookmark your favourite webpages to access them conveniently.</p>
	<p>Browsing webpages</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Internet</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap the address field.</p>
	<p>Enter the web address or a keyword, and then tap <MMI>Go</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To view the toolbars, drag your finger downwards slightly on the screen.</p>
	<p>To switch between tabs quickly, swipe to the left or right on the address field.</p>
	<p>Using secret mode</p>
	<p>In secret mode, you can separately manage open tabs, bookmarks, and saved pages. You can lock secret mode using a password and your biometric data.</p>
	<p>Activating secret mode</p>
	<p>In the toolbar at the bottom of the screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Turn on Secret mode</MMI>. If you are using this feature for the first time, set whether to use a password for secret mode.</p>
	<p>In secret mode, the device will change the colour of the toolbars.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>In secret mode, you cannot use some features, such as screen capture.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Changing security settings</p>
	<p>You can change your password or the lock method.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Privacy and security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Secret mode settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Change password</MMI>. To use your registered biometric data as a lock method along with the password, tap an option switch under <MMI>Biometrics</MMI> to activate it.</p>
	<p>Deactivating secret mode</p>
	<p>In the toolbar at the bottom of the screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Turn off Secret mode</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Camera</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Take photos and record videos using various modes and settings.</p>
	<p>Camera etiquette</p>
	<p>Do not take photos or record videos of other people without their permission.</p>
	<p>Do not take photos or record videos where legally prohibited.</p>
	<p>Do not take photos or record videos in places where you may violate other people’s privacy.</p>
	<p>Launching Camera</p>
	<p>Use the following methods to launch Camera:</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Press the Side key twice quickly.</p>
	<p>On the locked screen, drag <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> outside the circle.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some methods may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some camera features are not available when you launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app from the locked screen while the screen lock method is set.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If photos you take appear blurry, clean the camera lens and try again.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Taking photos</p>
	<p>Tap the image on the preview screen where the camera should focus.</p>
	<p>Spread two fingers apart on the screen to zoom in, and pinch to zoom out. Alternatively, drag the lens selection icon to the left or right. Zooming features are available only when using the rear camera.</p>
	<p>To adjust the brightness of photos, tap the screen. When the adjustment bar appears, drag the adjustment bar towards <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> or <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The preview screen may vary depending on the shooting mode and which camera is being used.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The camera automatically shuts off when unused.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Make sure that the lens is not damaged or contaminated. Otherwise, the device may not work properly in some modes that require high resolutions.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Your device’s camera features a wide-angle lens. Minor distortion may occur in wide-angle photos or videos and does not indicate device performance problems.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Locking the focus (AF) and exposure (AE)</p>
	<p>You can lock the focus or exposure on a selected area to prevent the camera from automatically adjusting based on changes to the subjects or light sources.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold the area to focus, the AF/AE frame will appear on the area and the focus and exposure setting will be locked. The setting remains locked even after you take a photo.</p>
	<p>Selecting a lens for shooting</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, select the lens you want and take a photo or record a video.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This feature is only available in some shooting modes.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : The wide-angle lens lets you take basic photos or record normal videos.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : The Ultra wide lens lets you take wide-angle photos or record wide-angle videos which look just like the actual view. Use this feature to take landscape photos.</p>
	<p>To correct the distortion in photos taken with the Ultra wide lens, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the preview screen, tap <MMI>Save options</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Ultra wide lens correction</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Using shooting modes</p>
	<p>To change the shooting mode, drag the shooting modes list to the left or right, or swipe to the left or right on the preview screen.</p>
	<p>Select a shooting mode you want.</p>
	<p>Photo mode (Intelligent camera)</p>
	<p>The camera adjusts the shooting options automatically depending on the surroundings to capture photos easily. The intelligent camera feature automatically recognises the subject and optimises the colour and any effects.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>PHOTO</MMI> and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo.</p>
	<p>Scene optimiser</p>
	<p>The camera adjusts the colour settings and applies the optimised effect automatically by recognising the subject.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>PHOTO</MMI>. When the camera recognises the subject, the scene optimiser button will change and the optimised colour and effect will be applied.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If this feature is not activated, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the preview screen and tap the <MMI>Scene optimiser</MMI> switch to activate it.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use additional features, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the preview screen, tap <MMI>Scene optimiser</MMI>, and then tap the switches next to the features you want.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you do not want to use this feature, tap the scene optimiser button on the preview screen.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Shot suggestions</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>The camera suggests the ideal composition for the photo by recognising the position and angle of your subject.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and tap the <MMI>Shot suggestions</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>A guide will appear on the preview screen.</p>
	<p>Point the guide at the subject.</p>
	<p>The camera recognises the composition, and the recommended composition appears on the preview screen.</p>
	<p>Adjust the position and angle of the camera to fit the composition.</p>
	<p>When the ideal composition is achieved, the guide will change to yellow.</p>
	<p>Taking selfies</p>
	<p>You can take self-portraits with the front camera.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>PHOTO</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, swipe upwards or downwards, or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to switch to the front camera for self-portraits.</p>
	<p>Face the front camera lens.</p>
	<p>To take self-portraits with a wide-angle shot of the landscape or people, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><xref/>Applying filter and beauty effects</p>
	<p>You can select a filter effect and modify facial features, such as your skin tone or face shape, before taking a photo.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Select a filter effect or beauty effects and take a photo.</p>
	<p>Video mode</p>
	<p>The camera adjusts the shooting options automatically depending on the surroundings to record videos easily.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>VIDEO</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To capture an image from the video while recording, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>To change the focus while recording a video, tap where you want to focus. To use auto focus mode, tap <MMI>AF</MMI> to cancel the manually set focus.</p>
	<p>Live focus mode</p>
	<p>Take photos that focus on the face by blurring the background. You can also apply a background effect and edit it after taking a photo.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use this feature in a place that has sufficient light.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The background blur may not be applied properly in the following conditions:</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>The device or the subject is moving.</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>The subject has a similar colour to the background.</UnorderList_2-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Taking portraits that stand out using the Live focus feature</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>LIVE FOCUS</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Drag the background blur adjustment bar to the left or right to adjust the blur level.</p>
	<p>When <MMI>Ready</MMI> appears on the preview screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo.</p>
	<p>Editing the background of the Live Focus photos</p>
	<p>You can also edit the background effect and the intensity of the background effect for a photo taken with the Live focus feature.</p>
	<p>Select a photo taken with the Live focus feature and tap <MMI>Change background effect</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a background effect you want.</p>
	<p>To adjust the intensity of the background effect, drag the adjustment bar to the left or right.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Apply</MMI> to save the photo.</p>
	<p>Super Slow-mo mode</p>
	<p>Super slow motion is a feature that records a quickly passing moment slowly so that you can appreciate it later. After the video is recorded, background music will be added automatically.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some super slow motion features may differ depending on the model.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Use this feature in a place that has sufficient light. When recording a video indoors with insufficient or poor lighting, some of the following situations may occur:</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>The screen may appear dark due to the small amount of light.</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>The screen may flicker in certain lighting conditions, such as in places with fluorescent lighting.</UnorderList_2-Cell><UnorderList_2-Cell>Noise may occur.</UnorderList_2-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Recording super slow motion videos</p>
	<p>Record a video by capturing a single moment that the subject is moving.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SUPER SLOW-MO</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>The device will capture the moment in super slow motion and save it as a video.</p>
	<p>Playing super slow motion videos</p>
	<p>Select a super slow motion video and tap <MMI>Play super slow-mo video</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Random background music will automatically accompany the video during playback.</p>
	<p>To capture an image while playing a video, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Editing super slow motion videos</p>
	<p>On the playback screen, you can edit the video and save it as a different file or share it.</p>
	<p>To crop out a desired section of the video, drag the start bracket and the end bracket to the desired points to select the section to keep.</p>
	<p>To edit the super slow motion section, drag <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to the left or right.</p>
	<p>Slow motion mode</p>
	<p>Record a video for viewing it in slow motion. You can specify sections of your videos to be played in slow motion.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SLOW MOTION</MMI>.</p>
	<p>When you are finished recording, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to stop.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, tap the preview thumbnail.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Play slow motion video</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The fastest section of the video will be set as a slow motion section and the video will start playing. Up to two slow motion sections will be created based on the video.</p>
	<p>To edit the slow motion section, drag <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to the left or right.</p>
	<p>Pro mode</p>
	<p>Capture photos while manually adjusting various shooting options, such as exposure value and ISO value.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>PRO</MMI>. Select options and customise the settings, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo.</p>
	<p>Available options</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an ISO value. This controls camera light sensitivity. Low values are for stationary or brightly lit objects. Higher values are for fast-moving or poorly lit objects. However, higher ISO settings can result in noise in photos.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an appropriate white balance, so images have a true-to-life colour range. You can set the colour temperature.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Change the exposure value. This determines how much light the camera’s sensor receives. For low-light situations, use a higher exposure.</p>
	<p>Separating the focus area and the exposure area</p>
	<p>You can separate the focus area and the exposure area.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold the preview screen. The AF/AE frame will appear on the screen. Drag the frame to the area where you want to separate the focus area and the exposure area.</p>
	<p>Panorama mode</p>
	<p>Using panorama mode, take a series of photos and then stitch them together to create a wide scene.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To get the best shots using panorama mode, follow these tips:</Description-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Move the camera slowly in one direction.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Keep the image within the frame on the camera’s viewfinder. If the preview image is out of the guide frame or you do not move the device, the device will automatically stop taking photos.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Avoid taking photos of indistinct backgrounds, such as an empty sky or a plain wall.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>PANORAMA</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and move the device slowly in one direction.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to stop taking photos.</p>
	<p>Food mode</p>
	<p>Take photos of food with more vibrant colours.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>FOOD</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the screen and drag the circular frame over the area to highlight.</p>
	<p>The area outside the circular frame will be blurred.</p>
	<p>To resize the circular frame, drag a corner of the frame.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and drag the adjustment bar to adjust the colour tone.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo.</p>
	<p>Night mode</p>
	<p>Take a photo in low-light conditions, without using the flash.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>NIGHT</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Hyperlapse mode</p>
	<p>Record scenes, such as passing people or cars, and view them as fast-motion videos.</p>
	<p>On the shooting modes list, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>HYPERLAPSE</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select a frame rate option.</p>
	<p>If you set the frame rate to <MMI>Auto</MMI>, the device will automatically adjust the frame rate according to the changing rate of the scene.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to start recording.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, tap the preview thumbnail and tap <MMI>Play hyperlapse</MMI> to view the video.</p>
	<p>Customising camera settings</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, use the following options.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The available options may vary depending on the shooting mode.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Activate or deactivate the flash.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select the length of the delay before the camera automatically takes a photo.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an aspect ratio for photos.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Apply beauty effects or a filter effect.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select a frame rate.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an aspect ratio for videos.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Stabilise a video.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>: Record fun videos with virtual handwriting or drawings on faces or anywhere else. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>AR Doodle</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select a metering method. This determines how light values are calculated. <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <MMI>Centre-weighted</MMI> uses the light in the centre portion of the shot to calculate the exposure of the shot. <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <MMI>Spot</MMI> uses the light in a concentrated centre area of the shot to calculate the exposure of the shot. <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <MMI>Matrix</MMI> averages the entire scene.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : In <MMI>Food</MMI> mode, focus on a subject inside the circular frame and blur the image outside the frame.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : In <MMI>Food</MMI> mode, adjust the colour tone.</p>
	<p>On the preview screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. Some options may not be available depending on the shooting mode.</p>
	<p><MMI>Intelligent features</MMI></p>
	<p><MMI>Scene optimiser</MMI>: Set the device to adjust the colour settings and apply the optimised effect automatically depending on the subject or scene.</p>
	<p><MMI>Shot suggestions</MMI>: Set the device to suggest the ideal composition for the photo by recognising the position and angle of your subject.</p>
	<p><MMI>Scan QR codes</MMI>: Enable or disable the QR code reader.</p>
	<p><MMI>Pictures</MMI></p>
	<p><MMI>Hold Shutter button to</MMI>: Select an action to perform when you tap and hold the camera button.</p>
	<p><MMI>Save options</MMI>: Select how you want to save photos.</p>
	<p><MMI>Videos</MMI></p>
	<p><MMI>Rear video size</MMI>: Select a resolution for videos you want to take with the rear camera. Using a higher resolution will result in higher quality videos, but they will take up more memory.</p>
	<p><MMI>Front video size</MMI>: Select a resolution for videos you want to take with the front camera. Using a higher resolution will result in higher quality videos, but they will take up more memory.</p>
	<p><MMI>High efficiency video</MMI>: Record videos in the High Efficiency Video Codec (HEVC) format. Your HEVC videos will be saved as compressed files to conserve the device’s memory.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You cannot play the HEVC videos on other devices or share them online.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Super slow motion and slow motion videos cannot be recorded in the HEVC format.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Video stabilisation</MMI>: Activate anti-shake to reduce or eliminate blurry image resulting from camera shake while recording a video.</p>
	<p><MMI>Useful features</MMI></p>
	<p><MMI>HDR (rich tone)</MMI>: Take photos with rich colours and reproduce details even in bright and dark areas.</p>
	<p><MMI>Pictures as previewed</MMI>: Set the device to save photos as they appear on the preview screen when taken with the front camera without flipping them.</p>
	<p><MMI>Grid lines</MMI>: Display viewfinder guides to help composition when selecting subjects.</p>
	<p><MMI>Location tags</MMI>: Attach a GPS location tag to the photo.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>GPS signal strength may decrease in locations where the signal is obstructed, such as between buildings or in low-lying areas, or in poor weather conditions.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Your location may appear on your photos when you upload them to the Internet. To avoid this, deactivate the location tag setting.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Shooting methods</MMI>: Select additional shooting methods for taking a photo or recording a video.</p>
	<p><MMI>Storage location</MMI>: Select the memory location for storage. This feature will appear when you insert a memory card.</p>
	<p><MMI>Watermark</MMI>: Add a watermark in the bottom left corner when taking pictures.</p>
	<p><MMI>Reset settings</MMI>: Reset the camera settings.</p>
	<p><MMI>About Camera</MMI>: View the Camera app version and legal information.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Gallery</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>View images and videos stored in your device. You can also manage images and videos by album or create stories.</p>
	<p>Viewing images</p>
	<p>Select an image.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can create an animated GIF or collage from multiple images. On the list, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Create GIF</MMI> or <MMI>Create collage</MMI>, and then select images.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Searching for images</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to view images sorted by category, such as types or locations.</p>
	<p>To search for images by entering keywords, tap the search field.</p>
	<p>Viewing videos</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Pictures</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a video to play.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Play video</MMI> to play the video.</p>
	<p>Drag your finger up or down on the left side of the playback screen to adjust the brightness, or drag your finger up or down on the right side of the playback screen to adjust the volume.</p>
	<p>To rewind or fast-forward, swipe to the left or right on the playback screen.</p>
	<p>Viewing the details of images and videos</p>
	<p>While viewing an image or on the video preview screen, drag upwards on the screen. File details will appear.</p>
	<p>You can also view related content by tapping information on the screen.</p>
	<p>Viewing photos or videos by category</p>
	<p>You can view photos and videos by category.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Pictures</MMI> or <MMI>Albums</MMI>, and then select a category.</p>
	<p><MMI>Videos</MMI>: View the videos saved in your device.</p>
	<p><MMI>Favourites</MMI>: View your favourite photos and videos.</p>
	<p><MMI>Recent</MMI>: View recent photos and videos.</p>
	<p><MMI>Suggested</MMI>: View recommended content.</p>
	<p>Viewing albums</p>
	<p>You can view your images and videos sorted by folders or albums.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Albums</MMI>, and then select an album.</p>
	<p>Hiding albums</p>
	<p>You can hide albums.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You cannot hide albums created by default, such as the <MMI>Camera</MMI> and <MMI>Screenshots</MMI> albums.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Albums</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Hide or unhide albums</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap an album switch to hide.</p>
	<p>Viewing stories</p>
	<p>When you capture or save images and videos, the device will read their date and location tags, sort the images and videos, and then create stories. To create stories automatically, you must capture or save multiple images and videos.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Stories</MMI>, and then select a story.</p>
	<p>Creating stories</p>
	<p>Create stories with various themes.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Create story</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter a title for the story and tap <MMI>Create</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tick images or videos to include in the story and tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To add images or videos to a story, select a story and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To remove images or videos from a story, select a story, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Edit</MMI>, tick images or videos to remove, and then tap <MMI>Remove from story</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Deleting stories</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Stories</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold a story to delete, and tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Syncing images and videos</p>
	<p>When you sync your <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app with Samsung Cloud, photos and videos you take will also be saved in Samsung Cloud. You can view images and videos saved in Samsung Cloud in your <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and from other devices.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Cloud sync</MMI> switch to activate it. The <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and Samsung Cloud will be synced.</p>
	<p>Deleting images or videos</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Select an image or a video to delete.</p>
	<p>To delete multiple files, tap and hold a file to delete on the list and tick more files to delete.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> or <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Using the recycle bin feature</p>
	<p>You can keep the deleted images and videos in the recycle bin. The files will be deleted after a certain period.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Recycle bin</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>To view files in the recycle bin, launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Recycle bin</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>AR EMOJI</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Create a My Emoji that looks just like you, and take photos and record videos using My Emojis, character Emojis, or stickers.</p>
	<p>You can customise My Emoji’s features, such as the face shape or hairstyle, and decorate My Emoji with various accessories. You can also express yourself in fun ways using My Emoji stickers during a conversation.</p>
	<p>Creating My Emoji</p>
	<p>Make a My Emoji that looks like you. My Emoji stickers with various expressions will be automatically generated.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list, and then tap <MMI>AR EMOJI</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Create My Emoji</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Align your face on the screen and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo.</p>
	<p>Select My Emoji’s gender and age range and tap <MMI>Next</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Decorate a My Emoji and tap <MMI>Next</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The My Emoji and My Emoji stickers are now created. You can view My Emoji stickers in the My Emoji Studio. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>My Emoji stickers</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can use the <MMI>AR EMOJI</MMI> feature in both the front and rear cameras. If you are using the rear camera, it will automatically switch to the front camera. To switch between cameras, swipe upwards or downwards on the preview screen.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Deleting My Emoji</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list, and then tap <MMI>AR EMOJI</MMI>. Tap and hold the My Emoji that you want to delete and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. The My Emoji and My Emoji stickers will be deleted.</p>
	<p>Customising My Emoji</p>
	<p>Edit or decorate a My Emoji in the My Emoji Studio. You can also create your own My Emoji stickers.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Available options may vary depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>My Emoji Studio</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list, and then tap <MMI>AR EMOJI</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Studio</MMI>. My Emoji Studio will appear.</p>
	<p><xref/>My Emoji stickers</p>
	<p>Create your own stickers with My Emoji expressions and actions. You can use My Emoji stickers when sending messages or on a social network.</p>
	<p>Viewing My Emoji stickers</p>
	<p>In the My Emoji Studio, tap <MMI>Stickers</MMI>. Then, you can view My Emoji stickers.</p>
	<p>Creating your own stickers</p>
	<p>In the My Emoji Studio, tap <MMI>Stickers</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Make custom stickers</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Edit stickers how you want.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Add stickers.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select the sticker’s background.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an expression.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Select an action.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Enter text.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Write or draw on stickers.</p>
	<p><xref/>Using My Emoji stickers in chats</p>
	<p>You can use My Emoji stickers during a conversation via messages or on a social network. The following actions are an example of using My Emoji stickers in the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>While composing a message in the <MMI>Messages</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the Samsung keyboard.</p>
	<p>Tap the My Emoji icon.</p>
	<p>Select one of the My Emoji stickers.</p>
	<p>The My Emoji sticker will be inserted.</p>
	<p>Deleting My Emoji stickers</p>
	<p>On the Samsung keyboard, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> at the bottom of the keyboard. Select the My Emoji stickers you want to delete and tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Capturing photos or videos with My Emoji</p>
	<p>Create fun photos or videos with My Emoji using various shooting modes.</p>
	<p>Select a My Emoji you want to use.</p>
	<p>Select the mode you want to use.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> (<MMI>Mask</MMI>): My Emoji’s face appears over your face so it looks like you are wearing a mask.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> (<MMI>Basic</MMI>): My Emoji mimics your expressions.</p>
	<p>Capturing photos or videos with character Emojis or stickers</p>
	<p>Character Emojis mimic your expressions. You can also apply sticker effects that follow your face.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app, tap <MMI>MORE</MMI> on the shooting modes list, and then tap <MMI>AR EMOJI</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a character Emoji, or tap <MMI>Stickers</MMI> and select a sticker you want to use.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to take a photo, or swipe to the left on the preview screen and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to record a video.</p>
	<p>You can view and share the photos and videos that you have captured in <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>AR Doodle</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Record fun videos with virtual handwriting or drawings on faces or anywhere else. When the camera recognises a face or space, the doodles on the face will follow the face as it moves, and the doodles in the space will be fixed in the same place even if the camera moves.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Camera</MMI> app and tap <MMI>VIDEO</MMI> on the shooting modes list.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select a mode you want.</p>
	<p>When the camera recognises the subject, the recognition area will appear on the screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Face</MMI>: Doodle on a face.</p>
	<p><MMI>Everywhere</MMI>: Doodle anywhere else.</p>
	<p>Write or draw in the recognition area.</p>
	<p>If you tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and begin to doodle, you can record yourself doodling.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to record a video.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to stop recording the video.</p>
	<p>You can view and share the video in <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Multi window</p>
	<p>Multi window lets you run two apps at the same time in the split screen view. You can also run multiple apps at the same time in the pop-up view.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some apps may not support this feature.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Split screen view</p>
	<p>Swipe to the left or right, tap an app’s icon, and then tap <MMI>Open in split screen view</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The selected app will launch in the upper window.</p>
	<p>On the lower window, swipe left or right to select another app to launch.</p>
	<p>To launch apps not on the list of recently used apps, tap the Home button or Back button and select an app.</p>
	<p>Adjusting the window size</p>
	<p>Drag the bar between the app windows up or down to adjust the size of the windows.</p>
	<p>When you drag the bar between the app windows to the top or bottom edge of the screen, the window will be maximised.</p>
	<p>Tap the Recents button to open the list of recently used apps.</p>
	<p>Swipe to the left or right, tap an app’s icon, and then tap <MMI>Open in pop-up view</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The app screen will appear in the pop-up view.</p>
	<p>Moving pop-up windows</p>
	<p>To move a pop-up window, tap the window’s toolbar and drag it to a new location.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Samsung Pay</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Register frequently used cards to Samsung Pay, a mobile payment service, to make payments quickly and securely. Samsung Pay supports near field communication (NFC) to allow payment through standard credit card readers.</p>
	<p>You can view more information, such as cards that support this feature at <C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com/samsung-pay</xref></C_URL>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use this feature, you must sign in to your Samsung account and register your biometric data. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Samsung account</xref></C_CrossReference> and <C_CrossReference><xref>Fingerprint recognition</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To make payments with Samsung Pay, the device may be required a connection to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network depending on the region.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>This app’s availability and supported features may vary depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The procedures for the initial setup and card registration may vary depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Setting up Samsung Pay</p>
	<p>When running this app for the first time or restart it after performing a data reset, follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the initial setup.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Samsung Pay</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Read and agree to the terms and conditions.</p>
	<p>Register your fingerprint to use when making payments.</p>
	<p>Create a PIN to use when making payments.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This PIN will be used to verify various actions in Samsung Pay, such as making payments and unlocking the app.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Registering cards</p>
	<p>You can easily register cards by capturing their images with the camera.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can check the cards that support this feature from the Samsung Pay website (<C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com/samsung-pay</xref></C_URL>).</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Samsung Pay</MMI> app and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete your card registration.</p>
	<p>Making payments</p>
	<p>Tap and hold a card image at the bottom of the screen and drag it upwards. Alternatively, launch the <MMI>Samsung Pay</MMI> app. Then, on the cards list, swipe to the left or right and select a card to use.</p>
	<p>Scan your fingerprint.</p>
	<p>Alternatively, enter the payment PIN you set when setting up the Samsung Pay.</p>
	<p>Touch the back of your device to the card reader.</p>
	<p>When the card reader recognises the card information, the payment will be processed.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Payments may not be processed depending on your network connection.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The verification method for payments may vary depending on the card readers.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Cancelling payments</p>
	<p>You can cancel payments by visiting the place where you made them.</p>
	<p>On the cards list, swipe to the left or right to select the card you used. Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete payment cancellation.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Samsung Health</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Samsung Health helps you manage your wellness and fitness. Set fitness goals, check your progress, and keep track of your overall wellness and fitness. You can also compare your step count records with other Samsung Health users, compete with your friends, and view health tips.</p>
	<p>Using Samsung Health</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Samsung Health</MMI> app. When running this app for the first time or restart it after performing a data reset, follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some features may not be available depending on the region.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>To add items to the Samsung Health home screen, tap <MMI>Manage items</MMI> at the bottom of the trackers list and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the items to add.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Together</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Together allows you to set up step count goals and compete with your friends. You can invite friends to walk together, set target step counts, compete in challenges, and view your ranking.</p>
	<p>On the Samsung Health home screen, tap <MMI>Together</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Steps</p>
	<p>The device counts the number of steps you take and measures the distance travelled.</p>
	<p>On the Samsung Health home screen, tap the steps tracker.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You may experience a brief delay while the steps tracker monitors your steps and then displays your step count. You may also experience a brief delay before the pop-up window indicates that your goal has been reached.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you use the steps tracker while travelling by car or train, vibration may affect your step count.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You can check your current steps on the notification panel. To turn off notifications, on the Samsung Health home screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Notifications</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Steps</MMI> switch under <MMI>Categories</MMI> to deactivate it. Alternatively, open the notification panel, tap and hold the notification, tap <MMI>Details</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Steps</MMI> switch to deactivate it.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Additional information</p>
	<p>Samsung Health is intended for fitness and wellness purposes only and is not intended for use in the diagnosis of disease or other conditions, or in the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease.</p>
	<p>The available functions, features and addable applications for Samsung Health may vary from country to country due to different local laws and regulations. You should check the features and applications available in your specific region before use.</p>
	<p>Samsung Health applications and its service can be changed or discontinued without prior notice.</p>
	<p>The purpose for data collection is limited to providing the service that you have requested, including providing additional information to enhance your wellness, sync data, data analysis and statistics or to develop and provide better services. (But if you sign in to your Samsung account from Samsung Health, your data may be saved on the server for data backup purposes.) Personal information may be stored until the completion of such purposes. You can delete personal data stored by Samsung Health by using the Erase personal data option in the Settings menu. To delete any data you have shared with social networks or transferred to storage devices, you must delete them separately.</p>
	<p>You may share and/or sync your data with additional Samsung services or compatible third party services that you select, as well as with any of your other connected devices. Access to Samsung Health information by such additional services or third party devices will only be permitted with your express approval.</p>
	<p>You assume full responsibility for the inappropriate use of data shared on social networks or transmitted to others. Use caution when sharing your personal data with others.</p>
	<p>If you use a wireless connection, such as Bluetooth, the device may be affected by electronic interference from other devices. Avoid using the device near other devices that transmit radio waves.</p>
	<p>Please read Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy of Samsung Health carefully before using it.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Samsung Members</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p><MMI>Samsung Members</MMI> offers support services to customers, such as device problem diagnosis, and lets users submit questions and error reports. You can also share information with others in the Galaxy users’ community or view the latest Galaxy news and tips. <MMI>Samsung Members</MMI> can help you solve any problems you might encounter while using your device.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To submit your feedback or post your comments, you must sign in to your Samsung account. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Samsung account</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Samsung Notes</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Create notes by entering text from the keyboard or by handwriting or drawing on the screen. You can also insert images or voice recordings into your notes.</p>
	<p>Creating notes</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Samsung Notes</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Select an input method from the toolbar at the top of the screen and compose a note.</p>
	<p>When you are finished composing the note, tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Deleting notes</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Samsung Notes</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap and hold a note to delete.</p>
	<p>To delete multiple notes, tick more notes to delete.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Galaxy Wearable</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Galaxy Wearable is an app that allows you to manage your wearable devices. When you connect your device to the wearable device, you can customise the wearable device’s settings and apps.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Galaxy Wearable</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Get started</MMI> to connect your device to the wearable device. Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to finish the setup. Refer to the wearable device’s user manual for more information about how to connect and use the wearable device with your device.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Calendar</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Manage your schedule by entering upcoming events or reminders in your planner.</p>
	<p>Creating events</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> or double-tap a date.</p>
	<p>If the date already has saved events or tasks in it, tap the date and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p>Enter event details.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Save</MMI> to save the event.</p>
	<p>Creating reminders</p>
	<p>You can create tasks as reminders and receive notifications at the preset time or location for each reminder. Launch the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reminder</MMI>. The <MMI>Reminder</MMI> app will launch. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Reminder</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p>Syncing events with your accounts</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI>, and then select the account to sync with.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Sync account</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>For the Samsung account, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Sync settings</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>To add accounts to sync with, launch the <MMI>Calendar</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add new account</MMI>. Then, select an account to sync with and sign in. When an account is added, a blue circle is displayed next to the account name.</p>
	<p>Radio</p>
	<p>Listening to the FM radio</p>
	<p>Before you use this app, you must connect an earphone, which serves as the radio antenna.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The FM radio scans and saves available stations automatically when running for the first time.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Playing through the speaker</p>
	<p>You can listen to the radio through the speaker instead of the connected earphone.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Play through speaker</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Scanning radio stations</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Radio</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Scan</MMI>. The FM radio scans and saves available stations automatically.</p>
	<p>Select the radio station you want from the stations list.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Voice Recorder</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Use this app to record or play voice memos.</p>
	<p>Making voice recordings</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Voice Recorder</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to start recording. Speak into the microphone.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to pause recording.</p>
	<p>While making a voice recording, tap <MMI>BOOKMARK</MMI> to insert a bookmark.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to finish recording.</p>
	<p>Enter a file name and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>My Files</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Access and manage various files stored in the device or in other locations, such as cloud storage services.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>My Files</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>View files that are stored in each storage.</p>
	<p>To check for unnecessary data and free up the device’s storage, tap <MMI>Analyse storage</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To search for files or folders, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Clock</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Set alarms, check the current time in many cities around the world, time an event, or set a specific duration.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Alarm</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Clock</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Alarm</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Setting alarms</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> in the alarms list, set an alarm time, select the days on which the alarm will repeat, set other various alarm options, and then tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To open the keypad to enter an alarm time, tap the time input field.</p>
	<p>To activate or deactivate alarms, tap the switch next to the alarm in the alarms list.</p>
	<p>Stopping alarms</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Dismiss</MMI> to stop an alarm. If you have previously enabled the snooze option, tap <MMI>Snooze</MMI> to repeat the alarm after a specified length of time.</p>
	<p>Deleting alarms</p>
	<p>Tap and hold an alarm, tick alarms to delete, and then tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>World Clock</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Clock</MMI> app and tap <MMI>World Clock</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Creating clocks</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, enter a city name or select a city from the map, and then tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To use the time zone converter, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Time zone converter</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Deleting clocks</p>
	<p>Tap and hold a clock, tick clocks to delete, and then tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Stopwatch</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Clock</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Stopwatch</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Start</MMI> to time an event.</p>
	<p>To record lap times while timing an event, tap <MMI>Lap</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Stop</MMI> to stop timing.</p>
	<p>To restart the timing, tap <MMI>Resume</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To clear lap times, tap <MMI>Reset</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Timer</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Clock</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Timer</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To add a frequently used timer, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, set the duration and name, and then tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Set the duration, and then tap <MMI>Start</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To open the keypad to enter the duration, tap the duration input field.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Dismiss</MMI> when the timer goes off.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Calculator</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Perform simple or complex calculations.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Calculator</MMI> app.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : View the calculation history. To clear the history, tap <MMI>Clear history</MMI>. To close the calculation history panel, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Use the unit conversion tool. You can convert various values, such as area, length, or temperature, into other units.</p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Display the scientific calculator.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Game Launcher</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Game Launcher gathers your games downloaded from <MMI>Play Store</MMI> and <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI> into one place for easy access. You can set the device to game mode to play games more easily.</p>
	<p>Using Game Launcher</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Game Launcher</MMI> app.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If <MMI>Game Launcher</MMI> does not appear, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Game Launcher</MMI> switch to activate it.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Drag the Library panel upwards and tap a game.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Games downloaded from <MMI>Play Store</MMI> and <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI> will be automatically shown on the Game Launcher screen. If you cannot see your games, drag the Library panel upwards and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Add apps</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Removing a game from Game Launcher</p>
	<p>Drag the Library panel upwards, tap and hold a game, and then tap <MMI>Remove from Game Launcher</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Changing the performance mode</p>
	<p>You can change the game performance mode.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Game Launcher</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Game performance</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Game performance</MMI>, and then select the mode you want.</p>
	<p><MMI>Focus on power saving</MMI>: This saves battery power while playing games.</p>
	<p><MMI>Balanced</MMI>: This balances the performance and the battery usage time.</p>
	<p><MMI>Focus on performance</MMI>: This focuses on giving you the best possible performance while playing games.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Battery power efficiency may vary by game.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Game Booster</p>
	<p>Game Booster lets you play games in a better environment and provides you with useful options via the Game Booster panel.</p>
	<p>Using Game Booster</p>
	<p>To open the Game Booster panel while playing games, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the navigation bar. If the navigation bar is hidden, drag upwards from the bottom of the screen to show it. If you have set the navigation bar to use <MMI>Full screen gestures</MMI>, open the notification panel and tap <MMI>Tap to open Game Booster</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You can set to open the Game Booster panel from the navigation bar while the navigation bar is set to <MMI>Full screen gestures</MMI>. On the Game Booster panel, tap <MMI>Block during game</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Full screen gestures</MMI> switch to activate it.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Available options may vary depending on the game.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> : Configure settings for Game Booster.</p>
	<p><MMI>Monitoring temperature</MMI> / <MMI>Monitoring memory</MMI>: Set the device to automatically adjust settings to prevent device overheating and to stop apps running in the background to better manage memory.</p>
	<p><MMI>Block during game</MMI>: Lock some features during games.</p>
	<p><MMI>Navigation button lock</MMI>: Hide the buttons on the navigation bar. To display the buttons, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the navigation bar.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screen touch lock</MMI>: Lock the touchscreen while the game is being played. To unlock the touchscreen, drag the lock icon in any direction.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screenshot</MMI>: Capture screenshots.</p>
	<p><MMI>Record</MMI>: Record your game sessions. To stop recording, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> on the navigation bar.</p>
	<p>Launching apps in pop-up windows while playing games</p>
	<p>You can launch apps in pop-up windows while playing a game.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select an app from the apps list.</p>
	<p>To edit the apps list, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Kids Home</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can restrict children’s access to certain apps, set their usage times, and configure settings to provide a fun and safe environment for children when they use the device.</p>
	<p>Using Kids Home</p>
	<p>Open the notification panel, swipe downwards, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> (<MMI>Kids Home</MMI>) to activate it. The Kids Home screen will appear. When starting Kids Home for the first time or after performing a data reset, follow the on-screen instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>On the Kids Home screen, select the app you want to use.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Your preset screen lock method or your created PIN will be used when activating the <MMI>Parental control</MMI> feature or closing Kids Home.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Using parental control features</p>
	<p>You can configure the settings for Kids Home and view the usage history.</p>
	<p>On the Kids Home screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Parental control</MMI> and enter your unlock code.</p>
	<p><MMI>Kid’s name</MMI>: Manage your child’s profile.</p>
	<p><MMI>Set daily playtime</MMI>: Restrict the usage time for Kids Home.</p>
	<p><MMI>Daily usage</MMI>: View the daily usage time of Kids Home.</p>
	<p><MMI>Activity</MMI>: View the activity history of Kids Home.</p>
	<p><MMI>Frequently contacted</MMI>: View the frequently used contacts in Kids Home.</p>
	<p><MMI>My kid’s creations</MMI>: View the works created from the apps in Kids Home.</p>
	<p><MMI>Allowed content</MMI>: Check the apps or content supported by Kids Home and add them.</p>
	<p><MMI>Show Content page</MMI>: Set the device to display the Samsung partner’s content page on the Kids Home screen.</p>
	<p>Closing Kids Home</p>
	<p>To close Kids Home, tap the Back button or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Close Kids Home</MMI>, and then enter your unlock code.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>SmartThings</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Control and manage smart appliances and Internet of Things (IoT) products with your smartphone.</p>
	<p><C_Important>Connecting with nearby devices</C_Important>: Connect with nearby devices, such as Bluetooth headsets or wearable devices, easily and quickly.</p>
	<p><C_Important>Registering and controlling home appliances, TVs, and IoT products</C_Important>: Register smart refrigerators, washers, air conditioners, air purifiers, TVs, and Internet of Things (IoT) products on your smartphone, and view their status or control them from your smartphone’s screen.</p>
	<p><C_Important>Receiving notification</C_Important>: Receive notifications from connected devices on your smartphone. For example, when the laundry is finished, you can receive a notification on your smartphone.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use SmartThings, your smartphone and other devices must be connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network. To fully use SmartThings, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The devices you can connect may vary depending on the region or service provider. Available features may differ depending on the connected device.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Connected devices’ own errors or defects are not covered by the Samsung warranty. When errors or defects occur on the connected devices, contact the device’s manufacturer.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Connecting to nearby devices</p>
	<p>Connect to nearby devices, such as Bluetooth headsets, easily and quickly.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Connection methods may vary depending on the type of connected devices or the shared content.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Scan</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a device from the list and connect to it by following the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions.</p>
	<p>Using home appliances, TVs, and IoT products</p>
	<p>View the status of your smart appliances, TVs, and IoT products from your smartphone’s screen. You can group devices by location and add rules to control the devices easily and conveniently.</p>
	<p>Connecting devices</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add device</MMI> or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add device</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a device type.</p>
	<p>Or, tap <MMI>Scan</MMI> or tap the search field to search for devices.</p>
	<p>You can also tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to connect devices by scanning the QR code.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to connect devices.</p>
	<p>Viewing and controlling connected devices</p>
	<p>You can view and control the devices. For example, you can check the ingredients in your refrigerator or adjust the TV volume.</p>
	<p>The list of connected devices will appear.</p>
	<p>View the status of devices on the list.</p>
	<p>To control the devices, select a device. When the device controller supplied with the selected device is downloaded, you can control the device.</p>
	<p>Adding devices and scenes by locations</p>
	<p>Add devices by locations, view the list of devices in a same location, and control them. You can also add a scene to a location to control multiple devices at the same time.</p>
	<p>Adding locations</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>SmartThings</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add location</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter the location name.</p>
	<p>To set a location, tap <MMI>Geolocation</MMI> to select a location on the map and tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To add rooms to the location, tap <MMI>Rooms</MMI>, tick rooms you want to add, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Your location will be added.</p>
	<p>To add devices to the location, tap <MMI>Add device</MMI> or tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add device</MMI> and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to register devices.</p>
	<p>Adding scenes</p>
	<p>Add a scene and register devices to it to control multiple devices at the same time.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Scenes</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add scene</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter the scene name.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> under <MMI>Actions</MMI> to add actions to perform.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Adding automations</p>
	<p>You can also set an automation to operate devices automatically depending on the preset time, the status of devices, and more.</p>
	<p>For example, add an automation to turn on the audio automatically every day at <C_NoBreak>7:00 AM</C_NoBreak>.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>SmartThings</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select a location.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Automations</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add automation</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> under <MMI>If</MMI>, set the activation conditions for the automation, and then tap <MMI>Next</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> under <MMI>Then</MMI>, set actions to perform, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter the automation name and tap <MMI>OK</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Receiving notifications</p>
	<p>You can receive notifications from connected devices on your smartphone. For example, when the laundry is finished, you can receive a notification on your smartphone.</p>
	<p>To set devices to receive notifications, launch the <MMI>SmartThings</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Notifications</MMI>, and then tap the switches next to the devices you want.</p>
	<p>Sharing content</p>
	<p>Share content by using various sharing options. The following actions are an example of sharing images.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You may incur additional charges when sharing files via the mobile network.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select a sharing method, such as message and email.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>When you have a communication or sharing history, the people you contacted will appear on the sharing options panel. To directly share content with them via the corresponding app, select a person’s icon. If the feature is not activated, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Direct share</MMI> switch to activate it.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Using additional features</p>
	<p><C_Important>Send to device</C_Important>: Share content with nearby devices via <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct or Bluetooth, or with SmartThings supported devices.</p>
	<p><C_Important>Smart View</C_Important>: View your device’s displayed content on a large screen by connecting your device to a screen mirroring-enabled TV or monitor.</p>
	<p><C_Important>Link Sharing</C_Important>: Share large files. Upload files to the Samsung storage server and share them with others via a Web link. To use this feature, your phone number must be verified.</p>
	<p>Samsung Global Goals</p>
	<p>The Global Goals, which were established by the United Nations General Assembly in 2015, consist of goals that aim to create a sustainable society. These goals have the power to end poverty, fight inequality, and stop climate change.</p>
	<p>With Samsung Global Goals, learn more about the global goals and join the movement for a better future.</p>
	<p>Google apps</p>
	<p>Google provides entertainment, social network, and business apps. You may require a Google account to access some apps.</p>
	<p>To view more app information, access each app’s help menu.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some apps may not be available or may be labelled differently depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Chrome</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Search for information and browse webpages.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Gmail</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Send or receive emails via the Google Mail service.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Maps</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Find your location on the map, search the world map, and view location information for various places around you.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>YT Music</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Enjoy various music and videos provided by YouTube Music. You can also view the music collections stored on your device and play them.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Play Movies &amp; TV</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Purchase or rent videos, such as movies and TV programmes, from <MMI>Play Store</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Drive</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Store your content on the cloud, access it from anywhere, and share it with others.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>YouTube</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Watch or create videos and share them with others.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Photos</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Search for, manage, and edit all your photos and videos from various sources in one place.</p>
	<p>Search quickly for items on the Internet or your device.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Duo</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Make a simple video call.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Settings</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Customise device settings. You can make your device more personalised by configuring various setting options.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>To search for settings by entering keywords, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Connections</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change settings for various connections, such as the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature and Bluetooth.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Wi-Fi</MMI>: Activate the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature to connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network and access the Internet or other network devices. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Wi-Fi</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Bluetooth</MMI>: Use Bluetooth to exchange data or media files with other Bluetooth-enabled devices. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Bluetooth</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Phone visibility</MMI>: Allow other devices to find your device to share content with you. When this feature is activated, your device will be visible to other devices when they search for available devices.</p>
	<p><MMI>NFC and payment</MMI>: Set the device to allow you to read near field communication (NFC) tags that contain information about products. You can also use this feature to make payments and buy tickets for transportation or events after downloading the required apps. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>NFC and payment</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Flight mode</MMI>: Set the device to disable all wireless functions on your device. You can use only <C_NoBreak>non-network</C_NoBreak> services.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Follow the regulations provided by the airline and the instructions of aircraft personnel. In cases where it is allowed to use the device, always use it in flight mode.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Mobile networks</MMI>: Configure your mobile network settings.</p>
	<p><MMI>Data usage</MMI>: Keep track of your data usage amount and customise the settings for the limitation. Set the device to automatically disable the mobile data connection when the amount of mobile data you have used reaches your specified limit.</p>
	<p>You can also activate the data saver feature to prevent some apps running in the background from sending or receiving data. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Data saver</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>SIM card manager</MMI> (dual SIM models): Activate your SIM or USIM cards and customise the SIM card settings. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>SIM card manager (dual SIM models)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Mobile Hotspot and Tethering</MMI>: Use the device as a mobile hotspot to share the device’s mobile data connection with other devices when the network connection is not available. Connections can be made via <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak>, USB, or Bluetooth. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Mobile Hotspot and Tethering</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>More connection settings</MMI>: Customise settings to control other features. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>More connection settings</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Wi-Fi</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Activate the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature to connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network and access the Internet or other network devices.</p>
	<p>Connecting to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network</p>
	<p>Select a network from the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> networks list.</p>
	<p>Networks that require a password appear with a lock icon. Enter the password and tap <MMI>Connect</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Once the device connects to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network, the device will reconnect to that network each time it is available without requiring a password. To prevent the device from connecting to the network automatically, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> next to the network and tap <MMI>Forget</MMI>.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you cannot connect to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network properly, restart your device’s <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature or the wireless router.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Wi-Fi Direct</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p><C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct connects devices directly via a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network without requiring an access point.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Wi-Fi</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>The detected devices are listed.</p>
	<p>If the device you want to connect to is not in the list, request that the device turns on its <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct feature.</p>
	<p>Select a device to connect to.</p>
	<p>The devices will be connected when the other device accepts the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct connection request.</p>
	<p>You can share data, such as contacts or media files, with other devices. The following actions are an example of sending an image to another device.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Wi-Fi Direct</MMI> and select a device to transfer the image to.</p>
	<p>Accept the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct connection request on the other device.</p>
	<p>If the devices are already connected, the image will be sent to the other device without the connection request procedure.</p>
	<p>Ending the device connection</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Wi-Fi</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Wi-Fi Direct</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The device displays the connected devices in the list.</p>
	<p>Tap the device name to disconnect the devices.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Bluetooth</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Use Bluetooth to exchange data or media files with other Bluetooth-enabled devices.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Samsung is not responsible for the loss, interception, or misuse of data sent or received via Bluetooth.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Always ensure that you share and receive data with devices that are trusted and properly secured. If there are obstacles between the devices, the operating distance may be reduced.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some devices, especially those that are not tested or approved by the Bluetooth SIG, may be incompatible with your device.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Do not use the Bluetooth feature for illegal purposes (for example, pirating copies of files or illegally tapping communications for commercial purposes). Samsung is not responsible for the repercussion of illegal use of the Bluetooth feature.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><xref/>Pairing with other Bluetooth devices</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bluetooth</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>The detected devices will be listed.</p>
	<p>Select a device to pair with.</p>
	<p>If the device you want to pair with is not on the list, set the device to enter Bluetooth pairing mode. Refer to the other device’s user manuals.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Your device is visible to other devices while the Bluetooth settings screen is open.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Accept the Bluetooth connection request on your device to confirm.</p>
	<p>The devices will be connected when the other device accepts the Bluetooth connection request.</p>
	<p>Sending and receiving data</p>
	<p>Many apps support data transfer via Bluetooth. You can share data, such as contacts or media files, with other Bluetooth devices. The following actions are an example of sending an image to another device.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Gallery</MMI> app and select an image.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bluetooth</MMI> and select a device to transfer the image to.</p>
	<p>If the device you want to pair with is not in the list, request that the device turns on its visibility option.</p>
	<p>Accept the Bluetooth connection request on the other device.</p>
	<p>Unpairing Bluetooth devices</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Bluetooth</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The device displays the paired devices in the list.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> next to the device name to unpair.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Unpair</MMI>.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>NFC and payment</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Your device allows you to read near field communication (NFC) tags that contain information about products. You can also use this feature to make payments and buy tickets for transportation or events after downloading the required apps.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The battery contains a built-in NFC antenna. Handle the battery carefully to avoid damaging the NFC antenna.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Reading information from NFC tags</p>
	<p>Use the NFC feature to read product information from NFC tags.</p>
	<p>Place the NFC antenna area on the back of your device near an NFC tag.</p>
	<p>The information from the tag appears.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Ensure that the device’s screen is unlocked. Otherwise, the device will not read NFC tags or receive data.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Making payments with the NFC feature</p>
	<p>Before you can use the NFC feature to make payments, you must register for the mobile payment service. To register or get more information about the service, contact your service provider.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> and tap the <MMI>NFC and payment</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Touch the NFC antenna area on the back of your device to the NFC card reader.</p>
	<p>To set the default payment app, open the Settings screen and tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>NFC and payment</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Tap and pay</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>PAYMENT</MMI>, and then select an app.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The payment services list may not include all available payment apps.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Sending data with the NFC feature</p>
	<p>Transfer data, such as images or contacts, with other devices by touching your device’s NFC antenna to the other device’s NFC antenna.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>NFC and payment</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Tap the <MMI>Android Beam</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Select an item and touch the other device’s NFC antenna to your device’s NFC antenna.</p>
	<p>When <MMI>Touch to beam.</MMI> appears on the screen, tap your device’s screen to send the item.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If both devices try to send data simultaneously, the file transfer may fail.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Data saver</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Reduce your data usage by preventing some apps running in the background from sending or receiving data.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Data usage</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Data saver</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>When the data saver feature is activated, the <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> icon will appear on the status bar.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To select apps to use data without restriction, tap <MMI>Allow app while Data saver on</MMI> and select apps.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Mobile data only apps</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Select apps to always use the mobile data even when your device is connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network.</p>
	<p>For example, you can set the device to use only mobile data for apps that you want to keep secure or streaming apps that can be disconnected. Even if you do not deactivate the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> feature, the apps will launch using the mobile data.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Data usage</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Mobile data only apps</MMI>, tap the switch to activate it, and then tap the switches next to the apps you want.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>SIM card manager</MMI_NoBold> (dual SIM models)</p>
	<p>Activate your SIM or USIM cards and customise the SIM card settings. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Using dual SIM or USIM cards (dual SIM models)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>SIM card manager</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Calls</MMI>: Select a SIM or USIM card for voice calls.</p>
	<p><MMI>Text messages</MMI>: Select a SIM or USIM card for messaging.</p>
	<p><MMI>Mobile data</MMI>: Select a SIM or USIM card for data services.</p>
	<p><MMI>Confirm SIM card for calls</MMI>: Set the device to ask which SIM or USIM card to use for the next call when you make a call without using your preferred SIM or USIM card for calls.</p>
	<p><MMI>Dual SIM always on</MMI>: Set the device to allow incoming calls from the other SIM or USIM card during a call.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>When this feature is enabled, you may incur additional charges for call forwarding depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Mobile Hotspot and Tethering</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Use the device as a mobile hotspot to share the device’s mobile data connection with other devices when the network connection is not available. Connections can be made via <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak>, USB, or Bluetooth.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Mobile Hotspot and Tethering</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You may incur additional charges when using this feature.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Mobile Hotspot</MMI>: Use the mobile hotspot to share the device’s mobile data connection with computers or other devices.</p>
	<p><MMI>Bluetooth tethering</MMI>: Use Bluetooth tethering to share the device’s mobile data connection with computers or other devices via Bluetooth.</p>
	<p><MMI>USB tethering</MMI>: Use USB tethering to share the device’s mobile data connection with a computer via USB. When connected to a computer, the device is used as a wireless modem for the computer.</p>
	<p>Using the mobile hotspot</p>
	<p>Use your device as a mobile hotspot to share your device’s mobile data connection with other devices.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Mobile Hotspot and Tethering</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Mobile Hotspot</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>The <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> icon appears on the status bar. Other devices can find your device in the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> networks list.</p>
	<p>To set a password for the mobile hotspot, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Configure Mobile Hotspot</MMI> and select the level of security. Then, enter a password and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On the other device’s screen, search for and select your device from the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> networks list.</p>
	<p>To connect without entering the password, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and scan the QR code with the other device.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If the mobile hotspot is not found, on your device, set <MMI>Band</MMI> to <MMI>2.4 GHz</MMI>, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Configure Mobile Hotspot</MMI>, and then deselect <MMI>Hide my device</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the connected device, use the device’s mobile data connection to access the Internet.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Auto Hotspot</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can share your device’s mobile data connection with other devices signed in to your Samsung account without entering a password.</p>
	<p>Tap the <MMI>Auto Hotspot</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>More connection settings</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Customise settings to control other connection features.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>More connection settings</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Nearby device scanning</MMI>: Set the device to scan for nearby devices to connect to.</p>
	<p><MMI>Printing</MMI>: Configure settings for printer plug-ins installed on the device. You can search for available printers or add one manually to print files. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Printing</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>MirrorLink</MMI>: Use the MirrorLink feature to control your device’s MirrorLink apps on the vehicle’s head unit monitor. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>MirrorLink</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>VPN</MMI>: Set up virtual private networks (VPNs) on your device to connect to a school or company’s private network.</p>
	<p><MMI>Private DNS</MMI>: Set the device to use the security enhanced private DNS.</p>
	<p><MMI>Ethernet</MMI>: When you connect an Ethernet adaptor, you can use a wired network and configure network settings.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Printing</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Configure settings for printer plug-ins installed on the device. You can connect the device to a printer via <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct, and print images or documents.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Some printers may not be compatible with the device.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Adding printer plug-ins</p>
	<p>Add printer plug-ins for printers you want to connect the device to.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>More connection settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Printing</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Download plugin</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Search for a printer plug-in in <MMI>Play Store</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a printer plug-in and install it.</p>
	<p>Select the installed printer plug-in.</p>
	<p>The device will automatically search for printers that are connected to the same <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network as your device.</p>
	<p>Select a printer to add.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To add printers manually, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Add printer</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Printing content</p>
	<p>While viewing content, such as images or documents, access the options list, tap <MMI>Print</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>All printers...</MMI>, and then select a printer.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Printing methods may vary depending on the content type.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>MirrorLink</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can display your device’s screen on the vehicle’s head unit monitor.</p>
	<p>Connect your device to a vehicle to control your device’s MirrorLink apps on the vehicle’s head unit monitor.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>More connection settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>MirrorLink</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Your device is compatible with vehicles that support MirrorLink version <C_FontChange>1.1</C_FontChange> or higher.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Connecting your device to a vehicle via MirrorLink</p>
	<p>When using this feature for the first time, connect the device to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</p>
	<p>Pair your device with a vehicle via Bluetooth.</p>
	<p>Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Pairing with other Bluetooth devices</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p>Connect your device to the vehicle using a USB cable.</p>
	<p>When they are connected, access your device’s MirrorLink apps on the head unit monitor.</p>
	<p>Ending the MirrorLink connection</p>
	<p>Unplug the USB cable from your device and the vehicle.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Sounds and vibration</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change settings for various sounds on the device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Sounds and vibration</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Sound mode</MMI>: Set the device to use sound mode, vibration mode, or silent mode.</p>
	<p><MMI>Vibrate while ringing</MMI>: Set the device to vibrate and play a ringtone for incoming calls.</p>
	<p><MMI>Temporary mute</MMI>: Set the device to use silent mode for a certain period.</p>
	<p><MMI>Ringtone</MMI>: Change the call ringtone.</p>
	<p><MMI>Notification sound</MMI>: Change the notification sound.</p>
	<p><MMI>Volume</MMI>: Adjust the device’s volume level.</p>
	<p><MMI>Vibration pattern</MMI>: Select a vibration pattern.</p>
	<p><MMI>System sound</MMI>: Set the device to sound for actions, such as controlling the touchscreen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Sound quality and effects</MMI>: Set the device’s sound quality and effects. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Dolby Atmos (surround sound)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Separate app sound</MMI>: Set the device to play media sound from a specific app separately on the other audio device. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Separate app sound</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Dolby Atmos</MMI_NoBold> (surround sound)</p>
	<p>Select a surround sound mode optimised for various types of audio, such as movies, music, and voice. With Dolby Atmos, you can experience moving audio sounds that flow all around you.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Sounds and vibration</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Sound quality and effects</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Dolby Atmos</MMI>, tap the switch to activate it, and then select a mode.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Before you use this feature, you must connect an earphone.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Separate app sound</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Set the device to play media sound from a specific app on the connected Bluetooth speaker or headset separate from the sound of other apps.</p>
	<p>For example, you can listen to the Navigation app through your device’s speaker while listening to playback from the Music app through the vehicle’s Bluetooth speaker.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Sounds and vibration</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Separate app sound</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Select an app to play media sounds separately and tap the Back button.</p>
	<p>Select a device for playing the selected app’s media sound.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Notifications</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the notification settings.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Notifications</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Suggest actions and replies</MMI>: Set the device to suggest actions and replies for notifications.</p>
	<p><MMI>Show snooze option</MMI>: Set whether to show the snooze option.</p>
	<p><MMI>App icon badges</MMI>: Change the settings for app icon badges.</p>
	<p><MMI>Status bar</MMI>: Set how to display notification icons and whether to show the remaining battery percentage on the status bar.</p>
	<p><MMI>LED indicator</MMI>: Set the device to turn on the LED indicator when you charge the battery, when you have notifications, or when you make voice recordings while the screen is turned off.</p>
	<p><MMI>Do not disturb</MMI>: Set the device to mute all sounds except for allowed exceptions.</p>
	<p><MMI>Recently sent</MMI>: View the apps that received recent notifications and change the notification settings. To customise notification settings for more apps, tap <MMI>See all</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>All</MMI> and select an app from the apps list.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Display</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the display and the Home screen settings.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Display</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Brightness</MMI>: Adjust the brightness of the display.</p>
	<p><MMI>Adaptive brightness</MMI>: Set the device to keep track of your brightness adjustments and apply them automatically in similar lighting conditions.</p>
	<p><MMI>Blue light filter</MMI>: Activate the blue light filter and change the filter settings. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Blue light filter</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Dark mode</MMI>: Reduce eye strain by applying the dark theme when using the device at night or in a dark place. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Dark mode</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Font size and style</MMI>: Change the font size and style.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screen zoom</MMI>: Change the screen zoom setting.</p>
	<p><MMI>Full screen apps</MMI>: Select apps to use with the full screen aspect ratio. You can also set the device to hide the front camera from the screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screen timeout</MMI>: Set the length of time the device waits before turning off the display’s backlight.</p>
	<p><MMI>Home screen</MMI>: Configure settings for the Home screen, such as the screen grid or layout.</p>
	<p><MMI>Easy mode</MMI>: Switch to easy mode to display larger icons and apply a simpler layout to the Home screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Navigation bar</MMI>: Change the navigation bar settings. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Navigation bar (soft buttons)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Touch sensitivity</MMI>: Increase the touch sensitivity of the screen for use with screen protectors.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screensaver</MMI>: Set the device to launch a screensaver when the device is charging. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Screensaver</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Blue light filter</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Reduce eye strain by limiting the amount of blue light emitted by the screen.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>While you are watching HDR videos from HDR-exclusive video services, the blue light filter may not be applied.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Display</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Blue light filter</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Turn on now</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Drag the adjustment bar to adjust the filter’s opacity.</p>
	<p>To set the schedule to apply the blue light filter to the screen, tap the <MMI>Turn on as scheduled</MMI> switch to activate it and select an option.</p>
	<p><MMI>Sunset to sunrise</MMI>: Set the device to apply the blue light filter at night and turn it off in the morning based on your current location.</p>
	<p><MMI>Custom schedule</MMI>: Set a specific time to apply the blue light filter.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Dark mode</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Reduce eye strain by applying the dark theme when using the device at night or in a dark place.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The dark theme may not be applied in some apps.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You can quickly activate or deactivate dark mode on the notification panel. Open the notification panel, swipe downwards, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> (<MMI>Dark mode</MMI>).</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Display</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Dark mode</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Turn on now</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>To set the schedule to apply dark mode to the screen, tap the <MMI>Turn on as scheduled</MMI> switch to activate it and select an option.</p>
	<p><MMI>Sunset to sunrise</MMI>: Set the device to turn on dark mode at night and turn it off in the morning based on your current location.</p>
	<p><MMI>Custom schedule</MMI>: Set a specific time to turn on and off dark mode.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Screensaver</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can set to display images as a screensaver when the screen turns off automatically. The screensaver will be displayed when the device is charging.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Display</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Screensaver</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select an option.</p>
	<p>If you select <MMI>Photo Frame</MMI> or <MMI>Photos</MMI>, a slideshow with selected images will start. If you select <MMI>Photo Table</MMI>, selected images will appear as small cards and overlap.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to select albums for displaying images.</p>
	<p>When you are finished, tap the Back button.</p>
	<p>To preview the selected option, tap <MMI>Preview</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>When you tap the screen while your screensaver is displayed, the screen will turn on.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Wallpaper</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the wallpaper settings for the Home screen and the locked screen.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Wallpaper</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Themes</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Apply various themes to the device to change the visual elements of the Home screen, locked screen, and icons.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Themes</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Themes</MMI>: Change the device’s theme.</p>
	<p><MMI>Wallpapers</MMI>: Change the wallpaper settings for the Home screen and the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Icons</MMI>: Change the icon style.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Lock screen</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the settings for the locked screen.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Lock screen</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The available options may vary depending on the screen lock method selected.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Screen lock type</MMI>: Change the screen lock method.</p>
	<p><MMI>Smart Lock</MMI>: Set the device to unlock itself when trusted locations or devices are detected. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Smart Lock</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Secure lock settings</MMI>: Change screen lock settings for the selected lock method.</p>
	<p><MMI>Wallpaper services</MMI>: Set the device to use wallpaper services such as Dynamic Lock screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Clock style</MMI>: Change the type and colour of the clock on the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Roaming clock</MMI>: Change the clock to show both the local and home time zones on the locked screen when roaming.</p>
	<p><MMI>FaceWidgets</MMI>: Change the settings of the items displayed on the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Contact information</MMI>: Set the device to show contact information, such as your email address, on the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Notifications</MMI>: Set how to show notifications on the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>Shortcuts</MMI>: Select apps to display shortcuts to them on the locked screen.</p>
	<p><MMI>About Lock screen</MMI>: View the Lock screen version and legal information.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Smart Lock</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>You can set the device to unlock itself and remain unlocked when trusted locations or devices are detected.</p>
	<p>For example, if you have set your home as a trusted location, when you get home your device will detect the location and automatically unlock itself.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>This feature will be available to use after you set a screen lock method.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you do not use your device for four hours or when you turn on the device, you must unlock the screen using the pattern, PIN, or password you set.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Lock screen</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Smart Lock</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select an option and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Biometrics and security</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the settings for securing the device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Biometrics and security</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Face recognition</MMI>: Set the device to unlock the screen by recognising your face. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Face recognition</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Fingerprints</MMI>: Register your fingerprints to unlock the screen. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Fingerprint recognition</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Biometrics preferences</MMI>: Change the settings for biometric data.</p>
	<p><MMI>Biometrics security patch</MMI>: View the version of the biometrics security patch and check for updates.</p>
	<p><MMI>Google Play Protect</MMI>: Set the device to check for harmful apps and behaviour and warn about potential harm and remove them.</p>
	<p><MMI>Find My Mobile</MMI>: Activate or deactivate the Find My Mobile feature. Access the Find My Mobile website (<C_URL><xref>findmymobile.samsung.com</xref></C_URL>) to track and control your lost or stolen device.</p>
	<p><MMI>Security update</MMI>: View the version of your device’s software and check for updates.</p>
	<p><MMI>Google Play system update</MMI>: View the Google Play system version and check for updates.</p>
	<p><MMI>Samsung Pass</MMI>: Verify your identity easily and securely via your biometric data. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Samsung Pass</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Install unknown apps</MMI>: Set the device to allow the installation of apps from unknown sources.</p>
	<p><MMI>Secure Folder</MMI>: Create a secure folder to protect your private content and apps from others. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Secure Folder</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Encrypt or decrypt SD card</MMI>: Set the device to encrypt files on a memory card.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If you reset your device to the factory defaults with this setting enabled, the device will not be able to read your encrypted files. Disable this setting before resetting the device.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Other security settings</MMI>: Configure additional security settings.</p>
	<p><xref/>Face recognition</p>
	<p>You can set the device to unlock the screen by recognising your face.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you use your face as a screen lock method, your face cannot be used to unlock the screen for the first time after turning on the device. To use the device, you must unlock the screen using the pattern, PIN, or password you set when registering the face. Be careful not to forget your pattern, PIN, or password.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you change the screen lock method to <MMI>Swipe</MMI> or <MMI>None</MMI>, which are not secure, all of your biometric data will be deleted. If you want to use your biometric data in apps or features, you must register your biometric data again.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> Precautions for using face recognition</p>
	<p>Before using the face recognition to unlock your device, keep the following precautions in mind.</p>
	<p>Your device could be unlocked by someone or something that looks like your image.</p>
	<p>Face recognition is less secure than Pattern, PIN, or Password.</p>
	<p>For better face recognition</p>
	<p>Consider the following when using face recognition:</p>
	<p>Consider the conditions when registering, such as wearing glasses, hats, masks, beards, or heavy makeup</p>
	<p>Ensure that you are in a well-lit area and that the camera lens is clean when registering</p>
	<p>Ensure your image is not blurry for better match results</p>
	<p>Registering your face</p>
	<p>For better face registration, register your face indoors and out of direct sunlight.</p>
	<p>Read the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions and tap <MMI>Continue</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select whether you are wearing glasses or not and tap <MMI>Continue</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Hold the device with the screen facing towards you and look at the screen.</p>
	<p>Position your face inside the frame on the screen.</p>
	<p>The camera will scan your face.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If unlocking the screen with your face is not working properly, tap <MMI>Remove face data</MMI> to remove your registered face and register your face again.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To enhance the face recognition, tap <MMI>Add alternative look</MMI> and add an alternate appearance.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Deleting the registered face data</p>
	<p>You can delete face data that you have registered.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Remove face data</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Remove</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Once the registered face is deleted, all the related features will also be deactivated.</p>
	<p><xref/>Unlocking the screen with your face</p>
	<p>You can unlock the screen with your face instead of using a pattern, PIN, or password.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Biometrics and security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Face recognition</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the <MMI>Face unlock</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you want to set the device to unlock the screen without swiping on the locked screen after recognising your face, tap the <MMI>Stay on Lock screen</MMI> switch to deactivate it.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you want to reduce the possibility of recognising faces in photos or videos, tap the <MMI>Faster recognition</MMI> switch to deactivate it. This may decrease the face recognition speed.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you want to increase the recognition rate in a dark place, tap the <MMI>Brighten screen</MMI> switch to activate it.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the locked screen, look at the screen.</p>
	<p>When your face is recognised, you can unlock the screen without using any additional screen lock method. If your face is not recognised, use the preset screen lock method.</p>
	<p><xref/>Fingerprint recognition</p>
	<p>In order for fingerprint recognition to function, your fingerprint information needs to be registered and stored in your device. After registering, you can set the device to use your fingerprint for the features below:</p>
	<p>Screen lock</p>
	<p>Secure Folder</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>This feature may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Fingerprint recognition uses the unique characteristics of each fingerprint to enhance the security of your device. The likelihood of the fingerprint sensor confusing two different fingerprints is very low. However, in rare cases where separate fingerprints are very similar the sensor may recognise them as identical.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you use your fingerprint as a screen lock method, your fingerprint cannot be used to unlock the screen for the first time after turning on the device. To use the device, you must unlock the screen using the pattern, PIN, or password you set when registering the fingerprint. Be careful not to forget your pattern, PIN, or password.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If your fingerprint is not recognised, unlock the device using the pattern, PIN, or password you set when registering the fingerprint, and then re-register your fingerprints. If your pattern, PIN, or password is forgotten, you will not be able to use the device if you do not reset it. Samsung is not responsible for any data loss or inconvenience caused by forgotten unlock codes.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you change the screen lock method to <MMI>Swipe</MMI> or <MMI>None</MMI>, which are not secure, all of your biometric data will be deleted. If you want to use your biometric data in apps or features, you must register your biometric data again.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>For better fingerprint recognition</p>
	<p>When you scan your fingerprints on the device, be aware of the following conditions that may affect the feature’s performance:</p>
	<p>The device may not recognise fingerprints that are affected by wrinkles or scars.</p>
	<p>The device may not recognise fingerprints from small or thin fingers.</p>
	<p>To improve recognition performance, register fingerprints of the hand used most often to perform tasks on the device.</p>
	<p>The Side key has a built-in fingerprint recognition sensor. Ensure that the fingerprint recognition sensor is not scratched or damaged by metal objects, such as coins, keys, and necklaces.</p>
	<p>Covering the fingerprint recognition sensor with protective films, stickers, or other accessories may decrease the fingerprint recognition rate. If the fingerprint recognition sensor is initially covered with a protective film, remove it before using the fingerprint recognition sensor.</p>
	<p>Ensure that the fingerprint recognition sensor and your fingers are clean and dry.</p>
	<p>If you bend your finger or use a fingertip, the device may not recognise your fingerprints. Make sure to cover the entire Side key with your finger.</p>
	<p>In dry environments, static electricity can build up in the device. Avoid using this feature in dry environments or before using the feature, discharge static electricity by touching a metal object.</p>
	<p>Registering fingerprints</p>
	<p>Read the on-screen instructions and tap <MMI>Continue</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Set a screen lock method.</p>
	<p>Place your finger on the Side key. After the device detects your finger, lift it up and place it on the Side key again.</p>
	<p>Repeat this action until the fingerprint is registered.</p>
	<p>When you are finished registering your fingerprints, tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Checking registered fingerprints</p>
	<p>You can check whether your fingerprint is registered by placing your finger on the fingerprint recognition sensor.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Check added fingerprints</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Place your finger on the fingerprint recognition sensor.</p>
	<p>The recognition result will be displayed.</p>
	<p>Deleting registered fingerprints</p>
	<p>You can delete registered fingerprints.</p>
	<p>Select a fingerprint to delete and tap <MMI>Remove</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Unlocking the screen with your fingerprints</p>
	<p>You can unlock the screen with your fingerprint instead of using a pattern, PIN, or password.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Biometrics and security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Fingerprints</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Unlock the screen using the preset screen lock method.</p>
	<p>Tap the <MMI>Fingerprint unlock</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>On the locked screen, place your finger on the fingerprint recognition sensor and scan your fingerprint.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Samsung Pass</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Register your biometric data to Samsung Pass and easily verify your identity when using services which require your login or personal information.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use this feature, your device must be connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or mobile network.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To use this feature, you must sign in to your Samsung account. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Samsung account</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The website sign-in feature is only available for websites that you access via the <MMI>Internet</MMI> app. Some websites may not support this feature.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Registered biometric data is only saved to your device and are not synced with other devices or servers.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Registering Samsung Pass</p>
	<p>Before using Samsung Pass, register your biometric data to Samsung Pass.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Biometrics and security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Samsung Pass</MMI>. Follow the on-screen instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>Verifying the Samsung account password</p>
	<p>You can use your registered biometric data to verify your identity instead of entering your Samsung account password when, for example, you purchase content from <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI>.</p>
	<p>On the Samsung Pass main screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Account and syncing</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Verify with Samsung Pass</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Using Samsung Pass to sign in to websites</p>
	<p>You can use Samsung Pass to easily sign in to websites that support ID and password autofill.</p>
	<p>Open a website that you want to sign in to.</p>
	<p>Enter your ID and password, and then tap the website’s sign in button.</p>
	<p>When a pop-up window asking whether you want to save the sign-in information appears, tick <MMI>Sign in with Samsung Pass</MMI> and tap <MMI>Remember</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Using Samsung Pass to sign in to apps</p>
	<p>You can use Samsung Pass to easily sign in to apps that support ID and password autofill.</p>
	<p>Open an app that you want to sign in to.</p>
	<p>Enter your ID and password, and then tap the app’s sign in button.</p>
	<p>When a pop-up window asking whether you want to save the sign-in information appears, tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Managing sign-in information</p>
	<p>View the list of websites and apps you have set to use Samsung Pass and manage your sign-in information.</p>
	<p>On the Samsung Pass main screen, tap <MMI>Sign-in</MMI> and select a website or app from the list.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Edit</MMI> and modify your ID, password, and the website’s or app’s name.</p>
	<p>To delete your sign-in information, tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Using Samsung Pass with websites and apps</p>
	<p>When using websites or apps that support Samsung Pass, you can easily sign in with Samsung Pass.</p>
	<p>To see the list of websites and apps that support Samsung Pass, on the Samsung Pass main screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Partners</MMI>. If there are no websites or apps that support Samsung Pass, <MMI>Partners</MMI> will not appear.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Available websites and apps may vary depending on the region or service provider.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Samsung is not responsible for any loss or inconvenience caused by signing in to websites or apps via Samsung Pass.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Entering your personal information automatically</p>
	<p>You can use Samsung Pass to easily enter your address or payment card information on apps that support personal information autofill.</p>
	<p>On the Samsung Pass main screen, tap <MMI>Autofill forms</MMI> and select <MMI>Add address</MMI> or <MMI>Add card</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter the information and tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>You can now use the biometric data you registered to Samsung Pass when entering the personal information automatically on supported apps.</p>
	<p>Deleting your Samsung Pass data</p>
	<p>You can delete your biometric data, sign-in information, and app data registered to Samsung Pass.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Your agreement to the terms and conditions and your Samsung account will remain active.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The Samsung Pass data on other devices signed in to your Samsung account will not be deleted.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the Samsung Pass main screen, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Delete data</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Enter your Samsung account password and tap <MMI>OK</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Your Samsung Pass data will be deleted.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Secure Folder</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Secure Folder protects your private content and apps, such as photos and contacts, from being accessed by others. You can keep your private content and apps secure even when the device is unlocked.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Secure Folder is a separate, secured storage area. The data in Secure Folder cannot be transferred to other devices via unapproved sharing methods, such as USB or <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct. Attempting to customise the operating system or modifying software will cause Secure Folder to be automatically locked and inaccessible. Before saving data in Secure Folder, make sure to back up a copy of the data in another secure location.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To use Secure Folder, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Setting up Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Biometrics and security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Agree to the terms and conditions of Secure Folder.</p>
	<p>Enter your Samsung account ID and password and tap <MMI>Sign in</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a lock method to use for Secure Folder and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the setup.</p>
	<p>The Secure Folder screen will appear and the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app icon (<C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>) will be added to the Apps screen.</p>
	<p>To change the name or icon colour of Secure Folder, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Customise</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>When you launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app, you must unlock the app using your preset lock method.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>If you forget your Secure Folder unlock code, you can reset it using your Samsung account. Tap the button at the bottom of the locked screen, and enter your Samsung account password.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Setting auto lock for Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Set the device to automatically lock Secure Folder when it is not being used.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Auto lock Secure Folder</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a lock option.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To manually lock your Secure Folder, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Lock and exit</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Moving content to Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Move content, such as photos and videos, to Secure Folder. The following actions are an example of moving an image from the default storage to Secure Folder.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Add files</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Images</MMI>, tick images to move, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Move</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The selected items will be deleted from the original folder and moved to Secure Folder. To copy items, tap <MMI>Copy</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The method for moving content may vary depending on the content type.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Moving content from Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Move content from Secure Folder to the corresponding app in the default storage. The following actions are an example of moving an image from Secure Folder to the default storage.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Gallery</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select an image and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Move out of Secure Folder</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The selected items will be moved to <MMI>Gallery</MMI> in the default storage.</p>
	<p>Adding apps</p>
	<p>Add an app to use in Secure Folder.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Add apps</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tick one or more apps installed on the device and tap <MMI>Add</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To install apps from <MMI>Play Store</MMI> or <MMI>Galaxy Store</MMI>, tap <MMI>Download from Play Store</MMI> or <MMI>Download from Galaxy Store</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Removing apps from Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Tap and hold an app to delete, and tap <MMI>Uninstall</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Adding accounts</p>
	<p>Add your Samsung and Google accounts, or other accounts, to sync with the apps in Secure Folder.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Accounts</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add account</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select an account service.</p>
	<p>Follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete the account setup.</p>
	<p>Hiding Secure Folder</p>
	<p>You can hide the Secure Folder shortcut from the Apps screen.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Show icon on Apps screen</MMI> switch to deactivate it.</p>
	<p>Alternatively, open the notification panel, swipe downwards, and then tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> (<MMI>Secure Folder</MMI>) to deactivate the feature.</p>
	<p>Backing up and restoring Secure Folder</p>
	<p>Back up content and apps in Secure Folder to Samsung Cloud using your Samsung account and restore them later.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add account</MMI> and follow the <C_NoBreak>on-screen</C_NoBreak> instructions to complete signing in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Back up Secure Folder data</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Data will be backed up to Samsung Cloud.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Backup and restore</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Restore</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to select a device to restore the data.</p>
	<p>Backed up data will be restored to your device.</p>
	<p>Uninstalling Secure Folder</p>
	<p>You can uninstall Secure Folder, including the content and apps in it.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI> app and tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>More settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Uninstall</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To back up content before uninstalling Secure Folder, tick <MMI>Move media files out of Secure Folder</MMI> and tap <MMI>Uninstall</MMI>. To access data backed up from Secure Folder, launch the <MMI>My Files</MMI> app and tap <MMI>Internal storage</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Secure Folder</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Notes saved in <MMI>Samsung Notes</MMI> will not be backed up.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Privacy</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change the settings for privacy.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Privacy</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Permission manager</MMI>: View the list of features and apps that have permission to use them. You can also edit the permission settings.</p>
	<p><MMI>Send diagnostic data</MMI>: Set the device to automatically send the device’s diagnostic and usage information to Samsung.</p>
	<p><MMI>Receive marketing information</MMI>: Set whether to receive Samsung marketing information, such as special offers, membership benefits, and newsletters.</p>
	<p><MMI>Advanced</MMI>: Configure advanced settings for privacy.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Location</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Change settings for location information permissions.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Location</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>App permissions</MMI>: View the list of apps that have permission to access the device’s location and edit the permission settings.</p>
	<p><MMI>Improve accuracy</MMI>: Set the device to use the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or Bluetooth feature to increase the accuracy of your location information, even when the features are deactivated.</p>
	<p><MMI>Recent location requests</MMI>: View which apps request your current location information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Location services</MMI>: View the location services your device is using.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Accounts and backup</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Sync, back up, or restore your device’s data using Samsung Cloud. You can also sign in to accounts, such as your Samsung account or Google account, or transfer data to or from other devices via Smart Switch.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Accounts</MMI>: Add your Samsung and Google accounts, or other accounts, to sync with.</p>
	<p><MMI>Backup and restore</MMI>: Keep your personal information, app data, and settings safe on your device. You can back up your sensitive information and access it later. You must sign in to your Google or Samsung account to back up or restore data.</p>
	<p><MMI>Samsung Cloud</MMI>: Manage the content that you want to store securely in Samsung Cloud. Check the usage status of your Samsung Cloud storage, and sync, back up, and restore your data. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Samsung Cloud</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Smart Switch</MMI>: Launch Smart Switch and transfer data from your previous device. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Transferring data from your previous device (Smart Switch)</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Regularly back up your data to a safe location, such as Samsung Cloud or a computer, so that you can restore it if the data is corrupted or lost due to an unintended factory data reset.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Samsung Cloud</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Sync the data saved in your device, such as images and videos, with Samsung Cloud and view the data you have saved on Samsung Cloud. You can also back up your device’s data to Samsung Cloud and restore it later.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>To use Samsung Cloud, you must sign in to your Samsung account.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Syncing data</p>
	<p>You can sync data saved in your device, such as images, videos, and events, with Samsung Cloud and access it from other devices.</p>
	<p>Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Sync and auto backup settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Sync</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the switches next to the items you want to sync with.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>You can check the saved data or change the settings by tapping <MMI>Gallery</MMI>, <MMI>Other synced data</MMI>, or <MMI>Samsung Cloud Drive</MMI>.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Backing up data</p>
	<p>You can back up your device’s data to Samsung Cloud.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Samsung Cloud</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Back up this phone</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tick items you want to back up and tap <MMI>Back up</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some data will not be backed up. To check which data will be backed up, on the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Samsung Cloud</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Back up this phone</MMI>.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>To view the backup data for other devices in your Samsung Cloud, on the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Samsung Cloud</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><MMI>Restore data</MMI><C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep><C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>, and then select a device you want.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Restoring data</p>
	<p>You can restore your backup data from Samsung Cloud to your device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accounts and backup</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Samsung Cloud</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Restore data</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> and select a device you want.</p>
	<p>Tick items you want to restore and tap <MMI>Restore</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Google</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Configure settings for some features provided by Google.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Google</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Advanced features</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Activate advanced features and change the settings that control them.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>Excessive shaking or an impact to the device may cause an unintended input for some features using sensors.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>XCover key</MMI>: View and edit the apps launched when you press the XCover key.</p>
	<p><MMI>Top key</MMI>: View and edit the apps launched when you press the Top key.</p>
	<p><MMI>Side key</MMI>: Select an app or feature to launch using the Side key. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Setting the Side key</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Bixby Routines</MMI>: Add routines to automate settings that you use repeatedly. The device also suggests useful routines according to your frequent situations. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Bixby Routines</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Call &amp; text on other devices</MMI>: Use your device’s calling and messaging features on other devices signed in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p><MMI>Link to Windows</MMI>: Instantly access data saved in your device on your computer. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Link to Windows</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Smart pop-up view</MMI>: Select apps to view their notifications via pop-up windows. When using this feature, you can quickly view the contents via pop-up windows by tapping the icon on the screen.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This feature is only available in apps that support the Multi window feature.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Screenshots</MMI>: Change the settings for screenshots.</p>
	<p><MMI>Direct share</MMI>: Set the device to display the people you contacted on the sharing options panel to allow you to share content directly.</p>
	<p><MMI>Reduce animations</MMI>: Set the device to reduce the screen effects of certain actions, such as opening or closing apps.</p>
	<p><MMI>Motions and gestures</MMI>: Activate the motion feature and configure settings. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Motions and gestures</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>One-handed mode</MMI>: Activate one-handed operation mode for your convenience when using the device with one hand.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This feature may not be available depending on the region or service provider.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Game Launcher</MMI>: Activate the Game Launcher. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Game Launcher</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Dual Messenger</MMI>: Install the second app and use two separate accounts for the same messenger app. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Dual Messenger</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Send SOS messages</MMI>: Set the device to send help messages by pressing the Side key three times.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Link to Windows</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Instantly access data saved in your device, such as photos and messages, on your computer by using the same Microsoft account on your computer as your device.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This feature is only available on Windows 10 version 1803 or higher, and it is recommended to use version 1903 or higher.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Link to Windows</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Sign in with Microsoft</MMI>, sign in to your Microsoft account, and then tap <MMI>Continue</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Show me</MMI> to view the computer setup procedures, follow the on-screen instructions to sign in on your computer, and then download the <MMI>Your Phone</MMI> app.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Continue</MMI> to complete the setup.</p>
	<p><xref/><MMI_NoBold>Motions and gestures</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Activate the motion feature and configure settings.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Motions and gestures</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Lift to wake</MMI>: Set the device to turn on the screen when you pick it up.</p>
	<p><MMI>Smart alert</MMI>: Set the device to alert you if you have missed calls or new messages when you pick up the device.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>This feature may not work if the screen is turned on or the device is not on a flat surface.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Easy mute</MMI>: Set the device to mute incoming calls or alarms by facing the device’s screen downwards.</p>
	<p><MMI>Direct call</MMI>: Set the device to make a voice call by picking up and holding the device near your ear while viewing message or contact details.</p>
	<p><MMI>Finger sensor gestures</MMI>: Set the device to open or close the notification panel when you swipe upwards or downwards on the fingerprint recognition sensor. This feature is not available when the sensor is detecting your fingerprint.</p>
	<p><MMI>Swipe to call or send messages</MMI>: Set the device to make a call or send a message when you swipe to the right or left on a contact or a phone number in the <MMI>Phone</MMI> or <MMI>Contacts</MMI> app.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Dual Messenger</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Install the second app and use two separate accounts for the same messenger app.</p>
	<p>Supported apps will appear.</p>
	<p>Tap the switch of an app to install the second app.</p>
	<p>The second app will be installed. The second app’s icon will be displayed with <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image>. When you receive notifications from the second app, the notifications will be displayed with <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> to distinguish them from the first app’s notifications.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The Dual Messenger feature may not be available depending on the app.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>Some features of the app may be limited for the second app.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Uninstalling a second app</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Advanced features</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Dual Messenger</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the switch of the app you want to uninstall and tap <MMI>Disable</MMI> or <MMI>Uninstall</MMI>.</p>
	<p>All data related to the second app will be deleted.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If you uninstall the first app, the second app will also be deleted.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Digital Wellbeing and parental controls</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Options</p>
	<p>View the history of your device usage and use features to prevent your device from interfering with your life. You can also set up parental controls for your children and manage their digital use.</p>
	<p><MMI>Digital Wellbeing</MMI>: View the daily usage history of your device. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Digital Wellbeing</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Parental controls</MMI>: Manage your children’s digital use.</p>
	<p><xref/>Digital Wellbeing</p>
	<p>View the daily usage history of your device. You can also limit usage time or change the notification settings for each app.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Digital Wellbeing and parental controls</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Digital Wellbeing</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Setting timers for apps</p>
	<p>You can limit the daily usage time for each app by setting a timer. When you reach the limit, the app will be deactivated and you cannot use it.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Digital Wellbeing and parental controls</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>App timers</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>No timer</MMI> next to the app you want and set the time.</p>
	<p>Using focus mode</p>
	<p>You can activate focus mode to avoid distractions from your device and stay focused on what you want. While focus mode is on, you can only use some apps such as <MMI>Phone</MMI>, <MMI>Clock</MMI>, and apps you allowed exceptions for.</p>
	<p>Adding focus mode</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Digital Wellbeing and parental controls</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap the mode name you want under <MMI>Focus mode</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To add your own mode, tap <MMI>Add</MMI> under <MMI>Focus mode</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Start</MMI>.</p>
	<p>For your own focus mode, enter the mode name, and then tap <MMI>Save</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Add</MMI>, tick apps you want to use, and then tap <MMI>Done</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Activating wind down mode</p>
	<p>You can activate wind down mode to reduce eye strain before sleeping and prevent your sleep from being disturbed.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Digital Wellbeing and parental controls</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Wind Down</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Start now</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To set the schedule to activate wind down mode, tap <MMI>Set a schedule</MMI>, tap the switch to activate it, and then set the days and time.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Device care</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Introduction</p>
	<p>The device care feature provides an overview of the status of your device’s battery, storage, memory, and system security. You can also automatically optimise the device with a tap of your finger.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Center><Img-Center/></Img-Center></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Optimising your device</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Optimise now</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The quick optimisation feature improves device performance through the following actions.</p>
	<p>Clearing some memory.</p>
	<p>Deleting unnecessary files and closing apps running in the background.</p>
	<p>Managing abnormal battery usage.</p>
	<p>Scanning for crashed apps and malware.</p>
	<p>Using the auto optimisation feature</p>
	<p>You can set the device to perform auto optimisation when your device is not in use. Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Advanced</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Auto optimisation</MMI> and tap the switch to activate it. If you want to set the time to perform auto optimisation, tap <MMI>Time</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Battery</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Check the remaining battery power and time to use the device. For devices with low battery levels, conserve battery power by activating power saving features.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Battery</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The usage time left shows the time remaining before the battery power runs out. Usage time left may vary depending on your device settings and operating conditions.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You may not receive notifications from some apps that use power saving mode.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Power mode</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Select a power mode that suits your device usage purposes.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Power mode</MMI> and select an option.</p>
	<p><MMI>Optimised</MMI>: Optimised for a balance between the device’s performance and battery usage.</p>
	<p><MMI>Medium power saving</MMI>: Activate power saving mode to extend the battery’s usage time.</p>
	<p><MMI>Maximum power saving</MMI>: In maximum power saving mode, the device decreases battery consumption by activating dark mode and limiting the apps and features available. Network connections, except for the mobile network, will be deactivated.</p>
	<p>You can set the device to charge the battery more quickly. Tap the <MMI>Fast cable charging</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Adaptive power saving</p>
	<p>You can set the device to activate power saving mode automatically based on your usage patterns and the remaining battery power.</p>
	<p>Tap <MMI>Power mode</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Adaptive power saving</MMI> switch to activate it. Your device will activate power saving mode based on the situation to extend the battery’s usage time.</p>
	<p>Managing battery usage for each app</p>
	<p>You can save battery power by preventing apps that are running in the background from using battery power when they are not being used. Tap <MMI>Battery usage</MMI>, select apps from the apps list, and then tap the <MMI>Put app to sleep</MMI> switch to activate the feature.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Storage</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Check the status of the used and available memory.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Storage</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>The actual available capacity of the internal memory is less than the specified capacity because the operating system and default apps occupy part of the memory. The available capacity may change when you update the device.</UnorderList_1-Cell><UnorderList_1-Cell>You can view the available capacity of the internal memory in the Specification section for your device on the Samsung website.</UnorderList_1-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Managing the memory</p>
	<p>To delete residual files, such as cache, tap <MMI>Clean now</MMI>. To delete files or uninstall apps that you do not use any more, select a category. Then, tick items to select and tap <MMI>Delete</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Memory</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Memory</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To speed up your device by stopping apps running in the background, tick apps from the apps list, and tap <MMI>Clean now</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Security</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Check the device’s security status. This feature scans your device for malware.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Device care</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Security</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Scan phone</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold><xref/>Apps</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Manage the device’s apps and change their settings. You can view the apps’ usage information, change their notification or permission settings, or uninstall or disable unnecessary apps.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Apps</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>General management</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Customise your device’s system settings or reset the device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>General management</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Language and input</MMI>: Select device languages and change settings, such as keyboards and voice input types. Some options may not be available depending on the selected language. Refer to <C_CrossReference><xref>Adding device languages</xref></C_CrossReference> for more information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Date and time</MMI>: Access and alter the settings to control how the device displays the time and date.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If the battery remains fully discharged or removed from the device, the time and date is reset.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Reset</MMI>: Reset your device’s settings or perform a factory data reset. You can reset all your settings, or only network settings, or accessibility settings. You can also set the device to restart at a preset time for device optimisation.</p>
	<p><xref/>Adding device languages</p>
	<p>You can add languages to use on your device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>General management</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Language and input</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Language</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Add language</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To view all the languages that can be added, tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>All languages</MMI>.</p>
	<p>Select a language to add.</p>
	<p>To set the selected language as the default language, tap <MMI>Set as default</MMI>. To keep the current language setting, tap <MMI>Keep current</MMI>.</p>
	<p>The selected language will be added to your languages list. If you changed the default language, the selected language will be added to the top of the list.</p>
	<p>To change the default language from your languages list, select the language you want and tap <MMI>Apply</MMI>. If an app does not support the default language, the next supported language in the list will be used.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Accessibility</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Configure various settings to improve accessibility to the device.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Accessibility</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Screen reader</MMI>: Activate Voice Assistant, which provides voice feedback. To view help information to learn how to use this feature, tap <MMI>Tutorial</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Visibility enhancements</MMI>: Customise the settings to improve accessibility for visually impaired users.</p>
	<p><MMI>Hearing enhancements</MMI>: Customise the settings to improve accessibility for users with hearing impairment.</p>
	<p><MMI>Interaction and dexterity</MMI>: Customise the settings to improve accessibility for users who have reduced dexterity.</p>
	<p><MMI>Advanced settings</MMI>: Configure settings for Direct access and notification features.</p>
	<p><MMI>Installed services</MMI>: View accessibility services installed on the device.</p>
	<p><MMI>About Accessibility</MMI>: View the Accessibility information.</p>
	<p><MMI>Contact us</MMI>: Ask questions or view frequently asked questions.</p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>Software update</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Update your device’s software via the firmware over-the-air (FOTA) service. You can also schedule software updates.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>Software update</MMI>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>If emergency software updates are released for your device’s security and to block new types of security threats, they will be installed automatically without your agreement.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI>Download and install</MMI>: Check for and install updates manually.</p>
	<p><MMI>Auto download over Wi-Fi</MMI>: Set the device to download updates automatically when connected to a <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> network.</p>
	<p><MMI>Last update</MMI>: View information about the last software update.</p>
	<p>Security updates information</p>
	<p>Security updates are provided to strengthen the security of your device and protect your personal information. For security updates for your model, visit <C_URL><xref>security.samsungmobile.com</xref></C_URL>.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell><Cell><Description-Cell>The website supports only some languages.</Description-Cell></Cell></Table></p>
	<p><MMI_NoBold>About phone</MMI_NoBold></p>
	<p>Access your device’s information.</p>
	<p>On the Settings screen, tap <MMI>About phone</MMI>.</p>
	<p>To change your device’s name, tap <MMI>Edit</MMI>.</p>
	<p><MMI>Status</MMI>: View various device information, such as the SIM card status, <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> MAC address, and serial number.</p>
	<p><MMI>Legal information</MMI>: View legal information related to the device, such as safety information and the open source licence.</p>
	<p><MMI>Software information</MMI>: View the device’s software information, such as its operating system version and firmware version.</p>
	<p><MMI>Battery information</MMI>: View the device’s battery status and information.</p>
	<p>Appendix</p>
	<p>Troubleshooting</p>
	<p>Before contacting a Samsung Service Centre, please attempt the following solutions. Some situations may not apply to your device.</p>
	<p>When you turn on your device or while you are using the device, it prompts you to enter one of the following codes:</p>
	<p>Password: When the device lock feature is enabled, you must enter the password you set for the device.</p>
	<p>PIN: When using the device for the first time or when the PIN requirement is enabled, you must enter the PIN supplied with the SIM or USIM card. You can disable this feature by using the Lock SIM card menu.</p>
	<p>PUK: Your SIM or USIM card is blocked, usually as a result of entering your PIN incorrectly several times. You must enter the PUK supplied by your service provider.</p>
	<p>PIN<C_FontChange>2</C_FontChange>: When you access a menu requiring the PIN<C_FontChange>2</C_FontChange>, you must enter the PIN<C_FontChange>2</C_FontChange> supplied with the SIM or USIM card. For more information, contact your service provider.</p>
	<p>Your device displays network or service error messages</p>
	<p>When you are in areas with weak signals or poor reception, you may lose reception. Move to another area and try again. While moving, error messages may appear repeatedly.</p>
	<p>You cannot access some options without a subscription. For more information, contact your service provider.</p>
	<p>Your device does not turn on</p>
	<p>When the battery is completely discharged, your device will not turn on. Fully charge the battery before turning on the device.</p>
	<p>The battery may not be inserted properly. Insert the battery again.</p>
	<p>Wipe both gold-coloured contacts and insert the battery again.</p>
	<p>The touchscreen responds slowly or improperly</p>
	<p>If you attach a screen protector or optional accessories to the touchscreen, the touchscreen may not function properly.</p>
	<p>If you are wearing gloves, if your hands are not clean while touching the touchscreen, or if you tap the screen with sharp objects or your fingertips, the touchscreen may malfunction.</p>
	<p>The touchscreen may malfunction in humid conditions or when exposed to water.</p>
	<p>Restart your device to clear any temporary software bugs.</p>
	<p>Ensure that your device software is updated to the latest version.</p>
	<p>If the touchscreen is scratched or damaged, visit a Samsung Service Centre.</p>
	<p>Your device freezes or encounters a fatal error</p>
	<p>Try the following solutions. If the problem is still not resolved, contact a Samsung Service Centre.</p>
	<p>Restarting the device</p>
	<p>If your device freezes or hangs, you may need to close apps or turn off the device and turn it on again.</p>
	<p>Forcing restart</p>
	<p>If your device is frozen and unresponsive, press and hold the Side key and the Volume Down key simultaneously for more than <C_NoBreak>7 seconds</C_NoBreak> to restart it.</p>
	<p>Resetting the device</p>
	<p>If the methods above do not solve your problem, perform a factory data reset.</p>
	<p>Launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app and tap <MMI>General management</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Factory data reset</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Delete all</MMI>. Before performing the factory data reset, remember to make backup copies of all important data stored in the device.</p>
	<p>Calls are not connected</p>
	<p>Ensure that you have accessed the right cellular network.</p>
	<p>Ensure that you have not set call barring for the phone number you are dialling.</p>
	<p>Ensure that you have not set call barring for the incoming phone number.</p>
	<p>Others cannot hear you speaking on a call</p>
	<p>Ensure that you are not covering the built-in microphone.</p>
	<p>Ensure that the microphone is close to your mouth.</p>
	<p>If using an earphone, ensure that it is properly connected.</p>
	<p>Sound echoes during a call</p>
	<p>Adjust the volume by pressing the Volume key or move to another area.</p>
	<p>A cellular network or the Internet is often disconnected or audio quality is poor</p>
	<p>Ensure that you are not blocking the device’s internal antenna.</p>
	<p>When you are in areas with weak signals or poor reception, you may lose reception. You may have connectivity problems due to issues with the service provider’s base station. Move to another area and try again.</p>
	<p>When using the device while moving, wireless network services may be disabled due to issues with the service provider’s network.</p>
	<p>The battery does not charge properly (For Samsung-approved chargers)</p>
	<p>Ensure that the charger is connected properly.</p>
	<p>If the battery terminals are dirty, the battery may not charge properly or the device may turn off. Wipe both gold-coloured contacts and try charging the battery again.</p>
	<p>The battery depletes faster than when first purchased</p>
	<p>When you expose the device or the battery to very cold or very hot temperatures, the useful charge may be reduced.</p>
	<p>Battery consumption will increase when you use certain features or apps, such as GPS, games, or the Internet.</p>
	<p>The battery is consumable and the useful charge will get shorter over time.</p>
	<p>Error messages appear when launching the camera</p>
	<p>Your device must have sufficient available memory and battery power to operate the camera app. If you receive error messages when launching the camera, try the following:</p>
	<p>Charge the battery.</p>
	<p>Restart the device. If you are still having trouble with the camera app after trying these tips, contact a Samsung Service Centre.</p>
	<p>Photo quality is poorer than the preview</p>
	<p>The quality of your photos may vary, depending on the surroundings and the photography techniques you use.</p>
	<p>If you take photos in dark areas, at night, or indoors, image noise may occur or images may be out of focus.</p>
	<p>Error messages appear when opening multimedia files</p>
	<p>If you receive error messages or multimedia files do not play when you open them on your device, try the following:</p>
	<p>Free some memory by transferring files to a computer or deleting files from your device.</p>
	<p>Ensure that the music file is not Digital Rights Management (DRM)-protected. If the file is DRM-protected, ensure that you have the appropriate licence or key to play the file.</p>
	<p>Ensure that the file formats are supported by the device. If a file format is not supported, such as DivX or AC<C_FontChange>3</C_FontChange>, install an app that supports it. To confirm the file formats that your device supports, visit <C_URL><xref>www.samsung.com</xref></C_URL>.</p>
	<p>Your device supports photos and videos captured with the device. Photos and videos captured by other devices may not work properly.</p>
	<p>Your device supports multimedia files that are authorised by your network service provider or providers of additional services. Some content circulated on the Internet, such as ringtones, videos, or wallpapers, may not work properly.</p>
	<p>Bluetooth is not working well</p>
	<p>If another Bluetooth device is not located or there are connection problems or performance malfunctions, try the following:</p>
	<p>Ensure that the device you wish to connect with is ready to be scanned or connected to.</p>
	<p>Ensure that your device and the other Bluetooth device are within the maximum Bluetooth range (<C_NoBreak>10 m</C_NoBreak>).</p>
	<p>On your device, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>Connections</MMI>, and then tap the <MMI>Bluetooth</MMI> switch to re-activate it.</p>
	<p>On your device, launch the <MMI>Settings</MMI> app, tap <MMI>General management</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset network settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset settings</MMI> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Reset</MMI> to reset network settings. You may lose registered information when performing the reset.</p>
	<p>If the tips above do not solve the problem, contact a Samsung Service Centre.</p>
	<p>A connection is not established when you connect the device to a computer</p>
	<p>Ensure that the USB cable you are using is compatible with your device.</p>
	<p>Ensure that you have the proper driver installed and updated on your computer.</p>
	<p>Your device cannot find your current location</p>
	<p>GPS signals may be obstructed in some locations, such as indoors. Set the device to use <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> or a mobile network to find your current location in these situations.</p>
	<p>Data stored in the device has been lost</p>
	<p>Always make backup copies of all important data stored in the device. Otherwise, you cannot restore data if it is corrupted or lost. Samsung is not responsible for the loss of data stored in the device.</p>
	<p>A small gap appears around the outside of the device case</p>
	<p>This gap is a necessary manufacturing feature and some minor rocking or vibration of parts may occur.</p>
	<p>Over time, friction between parts may cause this gap to expand slightly.</p>
	<p>There is not enough space in the device’s storage</p>
	<p>Delete unnecessary data, such as cache, using the device care feature or manually delete unused apps or files to free up storage space.</p>
	<p>The Home button does not appear</p>
	<p>The navigation bar containing the Home button may disappear while using certain apps or features. To view the navigation bar, drag upwards from the bottom of the screen.</p>
	<p>The screen brightness adjustment bar does not appear on the notification panel</p>
	<p>Open the notification panel by dragging the status bar downwards, and then drag the notification panel downwards. Tap <C_Image><C_Image/></C_Image> <C_SingleStep>→</C_SingleStep> <MMI>Quick panel layout</MMI> and tap the <MMI>Show brightness on top</MMI> switch to activate it.</p>
	<p>Copyright</p>
	<p>Copyright © 2019 Samsung Electronics</p>
	<p>This manual is protected under international copyright laws.</p>
	<p>No part of this manual may be reproduced, distributed, translated, or transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic or mechanical, including photocopying, recording, or storing in any information storage and retrieval system.</p>
	<p>Trademarks</p>
	<p>SAMSUNG and the SAMSUNG logo are registered trademarks of Samsung Electronics.</p>
	<p>Bluetooth<C_Superscript-R-TM>®</C_Superscript-R-TM> is a registered trademark of Bluetooth SIG, Inc. worldwide.</p>
	<p><C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak><C_Superscript-R-TM>®</C_Superscript-R-TM>, <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Direct<C_Superscript-R-TM>™</C_Superscript-R-TM>, <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> CERTIFIED<C_Superscript-R-TM>™</C_Superscript-R-TM>, and the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> logo are registered trademarks of the <C_NoBreak>Wi-Fi</C_NoBreak> Alliance.</p>
	<p>Manufactured under license from Dolby Laboratories. Dolby, Dolby Atmos, and the double-D symbol are trademarks of Dolby Laboratories.</p>
	<p>All other trademarks and copyrights are the property of their respective owners.</p>
	<p><Table><Cell><Img-Left><Img-Left/></Img-Left></Cell></Table></p>
	<p>Recognition area</p>
	<p>Change the pen type and colour.</p>
	<p>Redo</p>
	<p>Undo</p>
	<p>Create My Emoji.</p>
	<p>Select a My Emoji to edit.</p>
	<p>Change the My Emoji home screen's background.</p>
	<p>Edit the My Emoji.</p>
	<p>Create stickers.</p>
	<p>My Emojis</p>
	<p>Character Emojis</p>
	<p>Create your own stickers.</p>
	<p>Add stickers.</p>
	<p>My Emoji</p>
	<p>Mask</p>
	<p>Basic</p>
	<p>Mini motion</p>
	<p>Recommended content</p>
	<p>Upcoming reminder</p>
	<p>Experience the AR feature.</p>
	<p>Extract or translate text.</p>
	<p>Search for locations.</p>
	<p>Search for images.</p>
	<p>Preview thumbnail</p>
	<p>Take a photo.</p>
	<p>Scene optimiser button</p>
	<p>Current mode</p>
	<p>Shooting modes</p>
	<p>Select a lens</p>
	<p>Options for current shooting mode</p>
	<p>Switch between the front and rear cameras.</p>
	<p>Stickers</p>
	<p>Character Emoji</p>
	<p>Guide</p>
	<p>Ideal composition</p>
	<p> Ultra wide shooting</p>
	<p> Basic shooting</p>
	<p>Adjust the intensity of the background effect.</p>
	<p>Change the background effect.</p>
	<p>Slow motion section</p>
	<p>Super Slow-mo</p>
	<p>Start recording a video.</p>
	<p>Camera settings</p>
	<p>Start bracket</p>
	<p>End bracket</p>
	<p>Super slow motion section</p>
	<p>Change the background music.</p>
	<p>Select a storage location.</p>
	<p>Open more information fields.</p>
	<p>Enter contact information.</p>
	<p>Data saver feature activated</p>
	<p>The time the screen was on</p>
	<p>Set timers for apps.</p>
	<p>Number of unlocks</p>
	<p>Number of notifications</p>
	<p>Focus mode</p>
	<p>Second app</p>
	<p>Edge panel</p>
	<p>Edge panel settings</p>
	<p>Location information</p>
	<p>File details</p>
	<p>Edit information. </p>
	<p>People information</p>
	<p>Auto created content</p>
	<p>Modify the image.</p>
	<p>Add the image to favourites.</p>
	<p>Share the image with others.</p>
	<p>Delete the image.</p>
	<p>Bixby Vision</p>
	<p>Downloaded apps</p>
	<p>Library panel</p>
	<p>Open games with or without sound.</p>
	<p>View your gameplay information.</p>
	<p>Navigation bar (soft buttons)</p>
	<p>Favourite apps</p>
	<p>Edge panel handle</p>
	<p>Screen indicator</p>
	<p>A widget</p>
	<p>Apps button</p>
	<p>Bookmark the current webpage.</p>
	<p>View your bookmarks.</p>
	<p>Move between pages.</p>
	<p>Open the browser's tab manager.</p>
	<p>Refresh the current webpage.</p>
	<p>Open the homepage.</p>
	<p>Available apps</p>
	<p>Kids Phone</p>
	<p>Kids Gallery</p>
	<p>Kids Camera</p>
	<p>Background blur adjustment bar</p>
	<p>Colour point</p>
	<p>Zoom</p>
	<p>Spin</p>
	<p>Blur</p>
	<p>Locked screen</p>
	<p>Recipient</p>
	<p>Attach files.</p>
	<p>Enter stickers.</p>
	<p>Enter a message.</p>
	<p>Send the message.</p>
	<p>Enter recipients.</p>
	<p>Adjust the transparency level.</p>
	<p>Minimise the window.</p>
	<p>Maximise the window.</p>
	<p>Close the app.</p>
	<p>My Emoji icon</p>
	<p>Access the power options.</p>
	<p>View the notification details and perform various actions.</p>
	<p>Control media on your device and connected nearby devices.</p>
	<p>Launch <CharTag>Settings</CharTag>.</p>
	<p>Access the notification settings.</p>
	<p>Control connected nearby devices and SmartThings devices and scenes.</p>
	<p>Quick setting buttons</p>
	<p>Clear all notifications.</p>
	<p>Preview the phone number.</p>
	<p>Add the number to the contacts list.</p>
	<p>Search for a contact.</p>
	<p>View the list of available stations.</p>
	<p>Enter radio station frequency manually.</p>
	<p>View the list of favourite stations.</p>
	<p>Fine-tune the frequency.</p>
	<p>Search for an available radio station.</p>
	<p>Add the current radio station to the favourites list.</p>
	<p>Turn the FM radio on or off.</p>
	<p>Scan and save available stations automatically.</p>
	<p>Record audio from the FM radio.</p>
	<p>Reminder conditions</p>
	<p>Change the reminder's colour.</p>
	<p>Add an image.</p>
	<p>Add a checklist.</p>
	<p>Reminder information</p>
	<p>Enter a space.</p>
	<p>Delete a preceding character.</p>
	<p>Enter symbols.</p>
	<p>Break to the next line.</p>
	<p>Additional keyboard functions</p>
	<p>Enter uppercase. For all caps, tap it twice.</p>
	<p>View more keyboard functions.</p>
	<p>View and manage trackers.</p>
	<p>Compare your step count records with other Samsung Health users or compete with your friends.</p>
	<p>Monitor your health and fitness.</p>
	<p>View health tips.</p>
	<p>Current step total</p>
	<p>Target</p>
	<p>Battery</p>
	<p>Storage</p>
	<p>Security</p>
	<p>Memory</p>
	<p>Enter text using the keyboard.</p>
	<p>Paint with brushes.</p>
	<p>Write or draw with pens.</p>
	<p>Insert files.</p>
	<p>Select a calendar to save the event to.</p>
	<p>Enter the location.</p>
	<p>Add a note.</p>
	<p>Set an alarm.</p>
	<p>Enter a title.</p>
	<p>Add more details.</p>
	<p>Set the duration.</p>
	<p>Change the event's colour.</p>
	<p>Select a sticker to display with the event.</p>
	<p>Lock the playback screen.</p>
	<p>Pause and resume playback.</p>
	<p>Switch to the pop-up video player.</p>
	<p>Capture the current screen.</p>
	<p>Rewind or fast-forward by dragging the bar.</p>
	<p>Access additional options.</p>
	<p>Create an animated GIF.</p>
	<p>Rotate the screen.</p>
	<p>Skip to the next video. Tap and hold to fast-forward.</p>
	<p>Change screen ratio.</p>
	<p>Skip to the previous video. Tap and hold to rewind.</p>
	<p>Start recording.</p>
	<p>Change the recording mode.</p>
	<p>Split screen view</p>
	<p>Pop-up view</p>
	<p>Starting a conversation</p>
	<p>Listening</p>
	<p>Corresponding function launched</p>
	<p>"How's the weather today?"</p>
	<p>Sign in to your Samsung account.</p>
	<p>Select a language.</p>
	<p>Shooting modes list</p>
	<p>GPS antenna</p>
	<p>Earphone jack</p>
	<p>Rear camera (Quadruple)</p>
	<p>Microphone</p>
	<p>Main antenna</p>
	<p>Flash</p>
	<p>MST antenna (MST-enabled models)</p>
	<p>NFC antenna</p>
	<p>Home screen</p>
	<p>Apps screen</p>
	<p>Recents button</p>
	<p>Home button</p>
	<p>Back button</p>
	<p>Swipe from bottom</p>
	<p>Swipe from sides and bottom</p>
	<p>Speaker</p>
	<p>Volume key</p>
	<p>Side key (Power/Bixby)</p>
	<p>Multipurpose jack (USB Type-C)</p>
	<p>Proximity/Light sensor</p>
	<p>Front camera</p>
	<p>Touchscreen</p>
	<p>Fingerprint recognition sensor</p>
	<p>SIM card / Memory card tray</p>
	<p>Volume Down key</p>
	<p>Side key</p>
</Root>